<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<dataset>	
<pair id="H18-1-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="572"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A special provision that releases warranty can be made, but in that situation, when there are rights that the seller establishes on his/her own for a third party, the seller is not released of warranty.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-1-2" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="566"/>
<article id="567"/>
</t1>
<t2>
There is a limitation period on pursuance of warranty if there is restriction due to superficies on the subject matter, but there is no restriction on pursuance of warranty if the seller's rights were revoked due to execution of the mortgage.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-1-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="568"/>
<article id="570"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A compulsory auction is also a sale, so warranty is imposed the same as for an ordinary sale.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-2-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="697"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where a person plans to prevent crime in their own house by fixing the fence of a neighboring house, that person is found as having intent towards the other person.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-2-2" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="698"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where an individual rescues another person from getting hit by a car by pushing that person out of the way, causing the person's luxury kimono to get dirty, the rescuer does not have to compensate damages for the kimono.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-2-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="698"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A manager must engage in management exercising care identical to that he/she exercises for his/her own property..
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-2-4" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="702"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where a person repairs the fence of a neighboring house after it collapsed due to a typhoon, but the neighbor had intended to replace the fence with a concrete-block wall in the near future, if a separate typhoon causes the repaired sections to collapse the following week, reimbursement of repair fees can no longer be demanded.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-2-5" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="697"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even in cases when a parent, based on the authority of parents determined under the law, performs the business of the child as a statutory agent, Management of Business is established.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-3-2" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="715"/>
</t1>
<t2>
The employer is released from his/her liability in cases when proof is provided that the employer made proper care regarding the appointment and supervision of the employee.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-3-4" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="715"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even in cases when the victim has proven that authority of supervision has been granted to the agent supervisor from the employerprior to the act of injury of the employee, if proof is provided that the agent supervisor exercised reasonable care to the appointment and supervisionof the employee, the agent supervisor is released from liability.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-9-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="175"/>
<article id="265"/>
<article id="270"/>
<article id="280"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Usufructuary rights are only established for real estate.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-9-2" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="295"/>
<article id="303"/>
<article id="388"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Statutory real rights granted by way of security exist, but statutory usufructuary rights do not exist.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-9-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="329"/>
<article id="306"/>
<article id="330"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where real rights do not require requirements of perfection, the real rights that formed earlier in time take priority.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-15-1" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="398-20"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even if procedures for auctions petitioned by a lower rank security interest holder have begun, since the  first rank -revolving mortgagee has priority over the lower rank security interest holder regarding selection of the timing of the auction, the first rank revolving mortgagee can stop the auction procedures without fixing the principal.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-15-2" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="398-3"/>
</t1>
<t2>
If the principal is fixed, the revolving mortgage will be treated the same as an ordinary mortgage, and thus, interests or damages of secured claims secured by the revolving mortgage shall be limited to the amount of the last two years.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-15-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="398-2"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Since the  limit of performance received in priority by the revolving mortgage is determined by the  maximum amount, and  lower rank  security holders and  ordinary obligees do not possess interest in what kind of obligation will be secured,  the purpose  of the limit of the scope of the secured claim is to protect all mortgagors.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-15-4" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="398-7"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even before the principal of the revolving mortgage is fixed, the  third party that performed secured claims after the arrival of the due date can execute the revolving mortgage in subrogation of the revolving mortgager, in order to make the right to obtain reimbursement from the obligor secure.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-15-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="398-12"/>
<article id="398-13"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Since a  revolving mortgage before the fixing of principal  can be described as a right which dominates the value of the maximum amount  detached from the secured claim, it can be transferred in whole or in part, but since the obligor and the secured claim may change, approval must be obtained from the revolving mortgagor.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-20-1" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="9"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where an adult ward receives the gift of a building, the adult ward cannot rescindthe relevant gift contract.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-20-2" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="9"/>
<article id="120"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases when the adult ward performs juristic acts other than acts related to everyday life, even if the adult ward obtains approval from the guardian of the adult in advance for the relevant juristic act, the adult ward can rescindthe juristic act.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-20-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="7"/>
</t1>
<t2>
The minor that has been appointed a guardian of a minor cannot request a ruling for commencement of guardianship and be appointed a guardian of an adult.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-21-3" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="174-2"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Regarding delay in performance of a claim that occurred due to a commercial transaction, when a civil conciliation which states that the obligor will perform in installments is formed, the period of prescription for the relevant claim shall be 10 years.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-23-I" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="537"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where person A sold a jewel to person B, person B entered into a contract where person B was assigned to pay the purchase money to person C, and person C expressed his/her intention to enjoy the benefit of the contract, if person A delivered the jewel to person B, and person B has not paid the purchase money to person C yet, while person C can demand that person B should pay  the purchase money, person A can also demand that person B should pay the purchase money to person C.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-23-U" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="537"/>
<article id="538"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where person A sold a jewel to person B, and person B entered into a contract to pay the purchase money to person C as a performance of a loan obligation which A and D jointly and severally carry towards person C, if person D had already performed the obligation to person C, even after person C has expressed his/her intention to enjoy the benefit of the contract, person A can cancel  the contract upon agreement with person B.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-25-E" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="109"/>
</t1>
<t2>
a person who has manifested to a third party that he/she has granted certain authority of agency to other person(s) shall be relieved of his/her liability of apparent authority, if there is any proof  that the third party knew or was negligent  that the other person had not been granted authority of agency.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-26-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="255"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where person A and person B co-own building X at a ratio of 1:1, if person A dies and had no heirs or persons with special connection, ownership of building X belongs to person B.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-26-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="254"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where person A pays in advance management fees for a building co-owned by person A and person B, and person C receives  the share from person B, person A can demand that person C should  pay for person A's payments.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-27-U" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="485"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where the obligee changes residence to a faraway location prior to the due date for  performance, the obligor should bear the delivery costs of the object
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-28-1" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="446"/>
</t1>
<t2>
No contract of joint and several guarantee shall be effective unless it is made in writing, but a contract of guarantee shall be effective even if it is not made in writing.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-28-2" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="465-2"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where a contract of revolving guarantee the principal obligation of which is payment of purchase money upon a contract of continuous sales is made, if the maximum amount for the amount of the principal, any penalty and damages in connection with such principal obligation, and all other charges incidental to such obligation is not stipulated, the contract of revolving guarantee shall not be effective.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-28-3" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="465-4"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where the obligee has filed a petition for compulsory execution with respect to a claim the subject matter of which is payment of money on any property of the principal obligor, and the court ordered the commencement of such compulsory execution procedure, the principal for the principal obligation under  the contract for revolving guarantee on loans shall be  determined at the time of the filing.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-28-4" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="465-3"/>
</t1>
<t2>
For the principal obligation of a contract for revolving guarantee where the guarantor is an individual, in cases where the fixing date of the principal is specified as the day four years after the day that the contract was formed,  the fixing date of the principal is deemed to be the day three years after.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-29-4" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="419"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a demand for compensation based on delayed performance of loan claim, if person Y gives proof that the delayed performance is not based on the reasons attributable to him or herself, person Y shall be relieved of the liability.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-29-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="419"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where person X demands compensation of damages of 5% per annum from the day after the due date based on delay of performance of payment of sale purchase money, person X is not required to give proof of either occurrence of the damage  or the amount of it
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H18-32-5" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="192"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A seller that cancelled a movable sale contract on the basis of duress can demand return of the movable based on its ownership from the person who bought the movable from the buyer prior to the cancellation without knowledge or any negligence.
</t2>
</pair>
</dataset>
