<DOC>
<DOCNO>I</DOCNO>
General Provisions
Common Provisions
Fundamental Principles
Private rights must conform to the public welfare.
The exercise of rights and performance of duties must be done in good faith.
No abuse of rights is permitted.
Standard for Construction
This Code must be construed in accordance with honoring the dignity of individuals and the essential equality of both sexes.


Person
Capacity to Hold Rights
The enjoyment of private rights shall commence at birth.
Unless otherwise provided by applicable laws, regulations or treaties, foreign nationals shall enjoy private rights.

Capacity to Act
Age of Majority
The age of majority is reached when a person has reached the age of 20.
Juristic Act of Minors
A minor must obtain the consent of his/her statutory agent to perform any juristic act; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to an act merely intended to acquire a right or to be relieved of a duty.
A juristic act in contravention of the provision of the preceding paragraph may be rescinded.
Notwithstanding the provision of paragraph 1, in cases the statutory agent permits the disposition of property by specifying the purpose thereof, a minor may freely dispose of the same to the extent of such purpose. The same shall apply in cases his/her statutory agent permits the disposition of the property without specifying any purpose.
Permission for Minors to Carry on Business
A minor who is permitted to carry on one or more kinds of business shall have the same capacity to act as a person of the age of majority as far as such business is concerned.
In the case set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the minor may be unable to perform the relevant business for any reason, his/her statutory agent may revoke or limit permission in accordance with the provisions of
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>2</DOCNO>
Formalities of Wills
Ordinary Formality
Types of Will Made by Ordinary form
A will shall be made by holograph document, notarized document, or sealed and notarized document; provided that this shall not apply to the case where it is permissible to use a special method.
Will by Holograph Document
To make a will by holograph document the testator must write the entire text, the date, and his/her name in his/her own hand and affix his/her seal.
Unless, for an insertion, deletion or any other alteration to the handwritten certificate, the testator indicates the place of alteration, makes a specifically signed addition to the effect that it has been changed, and furthermore affixes his/her seal to the place that has been altered, it shall have no effect.
Will by Notarized Document
A will by notarized document shall be made in compliance with the following items:
Special Provisions for Will by Notarized Document
In the case where a will by notarized document is made by a person who cannot speak, the testator shall make a statement of the tenor of the will through an interpreter, or by his/her own hand, in lieu of the oral instruction of item (ii) of the preceding Article. In this case, in the application of the provision of item (iii) of the same Article, 'oral instruction' in that item shall become 'statement through an interpreter, or by his/her own hand'.
In the case where the testator or a witness of the preceding Article is deaf, a notary public may convey the written contents of the provision of item (iii) of the same Article to the testator or witness through an interpreter, in lieu of the reading aloud provided for in the same item.
If a notarized document has been made in compliance with the formalities provided for in the preceding paragraphs (1) and (2), a notary public shall give supplementary registration on the certificate to this effect.
Will by Sealed and Notarized Document
A will by sealed and notarized document shall be made in compliance with the following formalities:
The provision of paragraph (2) of Article 968 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the making of a will by sealed and notarized document.
Effect of Will by Sealed and Notarized Document Failing to Satisfy Formalities
Even a will by sealed and notarized document which fails to satisfy the formalities provided for in the preceding Article shall have effect as a will made by holograph document, if prepared in accordance with the formalities provided for in Article 968.
Special Provisions for Will by Sealed and Notarized Document
In the case where a will by sealed and notarized document is made by a person who cannot speak, the testator shall make a statement to the effect that the certificate is one's own will, giving the author's name and address through an interpreter, or by his/her own hand upon the sealed document, in lieu of the statement of item (iii) of paragraph (1) of Article 970.
In the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, if a testator has given a statement through an interpreter, a notary public shall make an entry on the sealed document to that effect.
In the case referred to in paragraph (1), if the testator has written on the sealed document is in his/her own hand, a notary public shall make an entry to that effect on the sealed document in lieu of the entry of statement in the provision of item (iv) of paragraph 1 of Article 970.
Will of an Adult Ward
For an adult ward to make a will at a time that his/her decision-making capacity has recovered temporarily, not less than two doctors shall be in attendance.
A doctor in attendance of the making of a will shall make an entry on the will to the effect that the testator was not in a condition lacking decision-making capacity at the time of making the will, sign it, and affix his/her seal; provided that in the case of a will by sealed and notarized document, he/she shall make an entry to that effect on the sealed document, sign it, and affix his/her seal.
Causes of Disqualification of Witness or Observer
The following persons may not be a witness or observer to a will:
Prohibition of Joint Wills
A will may not be made by two or more persons on the same certificate.
Special Formalities of Wills
Will Made by Person Rapidly Approaching Death
If a person who is rapidly approaching death due to illness or another reason intends to make a will, he/she may do so in the attendance of not less than three witnesses by giving oral instruction of the tenor of the will to one of the witnesses. In this case, the person who received the oral instruction shall enter this, read it aloud, or allow inspection, to the testator and other witnesses, and after each witness has approved the accuracy of that entry, sign it, and affix his/her seal.
In the case where a person who cannot speak makes a will pursuant to the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the testator shall state of the tenor of that will through an interpreter before the witnesses, in lieu of the oral instruction of the same paragraph.
In the case where the testator, or a witness, referred to in the second sentence of paragraph (1) is deaf, the person who has received the statement or oral instruction of the tenor of the will shall convey to the testator or other witnesses the written contents referred to in the provision of that sentence through an interpreter in lieu of the reading aloud provided for in that sentence.
For a will made pursuant to the provisions of the preceding three paragraphs, effect shall not arise unless it has been confirmed by the family court at the request of one of the witnesses or an interested party within twenty days of the creation of the will.
The family court may not confirm a will referred to in the preceding paragraph unless it is convinced that the will captured the true intention of the testator.
Will Made by Person with Infectious Disease in Quarantine
A person who is isolated through an administrative disposition due to an infectious disease may make a will in the attendance of one police official and at least one witness.
Will Made by Person on Vessel
A person on a ship may make a will in the attendance of the ship's captain or a clerk, and at least two witnesses.
Will Made by Person on Ship Meeting Disaster
In the case where a ship meets disaster, a person who is on that ship and rapidly approaching death may make a will orally in the attendance of at least two witnesses.
In the case where a person who cannot speak makes a will pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph, the testator shall do so through an interpreter.
The effect of a will made in compliance with the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall not arise unless a witness makes an entry of its tenor, signs this, affixes his/her seal, and furthermore, it gains confirmation by the family court at the request made without delay by one of the witnesses or an interested party.
The provision of paragraph (5) of Article 976 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case described in the preceding paragraph.
Signature and Seal of Relevant Parties to a Will
In the cases described in Article 977 and Article 978, a testator, author, observer, or witness shall sign and affix his/her seal to each will.
Case Where Signature or Seal Is Impossible
In the cases described in Articles 977 to 979 inclusive, if there is a person who is unable to sign or affix his/her seal, an observer or witness shall make supplementary registration of the reason for that.
Provisions Relating to Will by Ordinary Formalities to be Applied Mutatis Mutandis
The provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 968 and Articles 973 to 975 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to a will made pursuant to the provisions of Articles 976 to 981.
Effect of Will Made by Special Formalities
The effect of a will made pursuant to the provisions of Article 976 to 982 inclusive shall not arise if a testator survives for a period of six months from the time they recover the ability to make a will by ordinary formalities.
Formalities for Japanese National in Foreign Country
For a Japanese national in a foreign country where a Japanese consulate is stationed to make a will by notarized document, or a sealed and notarized document, the duties of a notary public shall be undertaken by the consulate.

Effect of Will
When Effect of Will Arises
A will takes effect at the time of the testator's death.
In the case where a will is subject to a condition precedent, if that condition is fulfilled after the death of the testator, the will shall take effect from the time that condition is fulfilled.
Renunciation of Testamentary Gift
A testamentary donee may renounce a testamentary gift at any time after the death of a testator.
The renunciation of a testamentary gift shall have retroactive effect from the time of the testator's death.
Notice to Testamentary Donees for Acceptance or Renunciation of a Testamentary Gift
A person with a duty of testamentary gift (in this Section, a person who bears a duty to perform a testamentary gift) or any other interested party may give notice to a testamentary donee to the effect that acceptance or renunciation of a testamentary gift should be made within a specified period, fixing a period that is reasonable. In this case, if a donee does not indicate his/her intention to a person with a duty of testamentary gift within that period, the testamentary gift shall be deemed to have been accepted.
Acceptance or Renunciation of Testamentary Gift by Heir or Testamentary Donee
If a testamentary donee dies without having made acceptance or renunciation of a testamentary gift, the heir of that person may accept or renounce the testamentary gift within the extent of his/her share in inheritance; provided that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, this intent shall be complied with.
Revocation and Rescission of Acceptance and Renunciation of Testamentary Gift
Acceptance or renunciation of a testamentary gift may not be revoked.
The provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) of Article 919 shall apply mutatis mutandis to acceptance and renunciation of a testamentary gift.
Rights and Duties of Testamentary Donee by a Universal Succession
A testamentary donee by a universal succession shall have the same rights as an heir.
Claim for Security by a Testamentary Donee
While a testamentary gift is not due, a testamentary donee may make a claim for reasonable security from a person having an obligation with respect to testamentary gift. The same shall also apply for a testamentary gift with a condition precedent while the outcome of that condition is unknown.
Collecting Fruits of Testamentary Gift
A testamentary donee may collect the fruits of a testamentary gift from the time that they are able to make a claim for the performance of that gift; provided that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Claim for Reimbursement of Expenses Incurred by Person with Duty of Testamentary Gift
The provisions of Article 299 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where expenses have been incurred by a person with a duty of testamentary gift in respect of the object of the testamentary gift after the death of the testator.
An application for reimbursement may be made for normal necessary expenses incurred in collecting the fruits of a testamentary gift, limited to an amount not exceeding the value of those fruits.
Lapse of Testamentary Gift through Death of Donee
The effect of a testamentary gift shall not arise if the testamentary donee dies before the death of the testator.
The preceding paragraph shall also apply if, in the case of a testamentary gift with a condition precedent, the testamentary donee dies before the fulfillment of that condition; provided, however, that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Ownership of Property in Case of Invalidation or Lapse of Testamentary Gift
If the effect of a testamentary gift does not arise, or if its effect is lost by renunciation, that which should have been received by the testamentary donee shall belong to the heir(s); provided, however, that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Testamentary Gift of Rights Not Belonging to Inherited Property
A testamentary gift shall not take effect if the rights which are the object of that gift did not belong to the inherited property at the time of the testator's death; provided, however, that this shall not apply if it is found that those rights were made the object of a testamentary gift regardless of whether such rights belong to the inherited property.
If a testamentary gift, the object of which are rights that do not belong to the inherited property, has effect pursuant to the provision of the proviso to the preceding Article, the person with a duty of testamentary gift shall bear a duty to obtain those rights and transfer them to the testamentary donee.
In the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, if the rights referred to in that paragraph cannot be obtained, or if obtaining them requires excessive expenses, a person with a duty of testamentary gift shall give compensation to the value of those rights; provided, however, that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Warranty Liability of Person Having Obligation for to Testamentary Gift for Unspecified Things
In the case where a testamentary gift has as its object unspecified Things but a third party as a rightful claimant retakes them from a testamentary donee, a person having an obligation in relation to testamentary gift shall be liable under the same warranty with respect to those unspecified Things, just as a seller.
In the case where a testamentary gift has as its object unspecified Things, if those goods are defective, a person having an obligation in relation to testamentary gift shall exchange them for Things that are not defective.
Extension of Testamentary Gift over Right to Claim from Third Party
If a testator has a right to claim compensation from a third party resulting from loss or alteration, or loss of possession, of the object of a testamentary gift, that right shall be presumed to have been an object of the testamentary gift.
In the case of accession or mixture of the object of a testamentary gift with other Things, if a testator has become a sole owner or co-owner of a compound or mixture pursuant to the provisions of Articles 243 to 245 inclusive, that entire ownership, or share, shall be presumed to have been an object of the testamentary gift.
Testamentary Gift of Property Subject to the Rights of Third party
If Things or rights being the object of a testamentary gift were the object of the rights of a third party at the time of the testator's death, a testamentary donee may not demand a person having an obligation with respect to testamentary gift to extinguish the third party's rights; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the testator has indicated a contrary intent in his/her will.
Extension of Testamentary Gift over Things Received for Satisfaction of Claim
In the case where a claim is the object of a testamentary gift, if the testator has received performance for that claim and the received Things are already with the inherited property, those Things shall be presumed to have been an object of the testamentary gift.
In the case where money is the object of a claim which is the object of a testamentary gift, that money shall be presumed to have been an object of the testamentary gift even if there are insufficient funds equivalent to that claim in the inherited property.
Testamentary Gift with Burden
A person who has received a testamentary gift with burden shall bear a responsibility to perform the duties borne, limited to an amount not exceeding the object of the testamentary gift.
If a testamentary donee has renounced a testamentary gift with burden, the person who would have received gain from the discharge of burden may become a testamentary donee him/herself; provided that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Discharge of Testamentary Donee of Testamentary Gift with Burden
If the value of an object of a testamentary gift with burden is reduced due to the qualified acceptance of an heir, or a filing for recovery of legally reserved portion, a testamentary donee may avoid the duties borne from that testamentary gift, proportional to the reduction; provided, however, that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.

Execution of Will
Probate of Will
A custodian of a will, after coming to know of the commencement of inheritance, shall without delay submit the will to the family court and apply for probate. In the case where there is no custodian of a will, the same shall apply after an heir discovers the will.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply to a will made by notarized document.
A will that has been sealed may not be opened unless in the family court in the attendance of an heir or his/her representative.
Civil Fine
A person who fails to submit a will pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article, executes a will without passing through probate, or opens a sealed will in a place other than a family court shall be made subject to a civil fine of not more than 50,000 yen.
Designation of Executor
A testator may, by will, designate one or several executors, or entrust that designation to a third party.
A person who has been entrusted with the designation of an executor shall, without delay, make that designation and inform the heir(s) of the designation.
If a person who has been entrusted with the designation of an executor intends to resign from that entrustment, he/she shall notify the heir(s) to that effect without delay.
Commencement of Duties of Executor
If an executor consents to taking office, he/she shall undertake his/her duties immediately.
Notice of Taking Office to Executor
An heir or other interested party may, having specified a reasonable period, make a demand to an executor to the effect that that he/she make a definite answer within that period as to whether he/she consents to taking office. In this case, if the executor does not make a definite answer to the heir within this period, he/she shall be deemed to have consented to taking office.
Causes for Disqualification of Executor
A minor or a bankrupt may not become an executor.
Appointment of Executor
If an executor does not exist, or the office becomes vacant, the family court may appoint an executor at the request of an interested party.
Preparation of Inventory of Inherited Property
An executor shall, without delay, prepare an inventory of inherited property and deliver this to the heir(s).
At the request of an heir, an executor shall prepare an inventory of inherited property in the heir's attendance, or have a notary public create the inventory.
Rights and Duties of Executor
An executor shall have the rights and duties of administration of inherited property and all other necessary acts for the execution of a will.
The provisions of Articles 644 to 647 inclusive and 650 shall apply mutatis mutandis to an executor.
Prohibition of Interference with Execution of Will
In the case where there is an executor, an heir may not make a disposition of inherited property or any other act that interferes with the execution of the will.
Execution of Will concerning Specified Property
In the case where a will concerns specified property in the inherited property, the provisions of Articles 1011 to 1013 inclusive shall only apply to that specified property.
Status of Executor
An executor shall be deemed the representative of the heir(s).
Executor's Right to Appoint Subagent
An executor may not allow a third party to undertake the duties of an executor unless there are justifiable reasons; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the testator has indicated a contrary intent in his/her will.
In the case where an executor has allowed a third party to undertake the duties of an executor pursuant to the provision in the proviso to the preceding paragraph, the executor shall owe the responsibility referred to in Article 105 to the heir(s).
Execution of Duties Where Two or More Executors
In the case where there are two or more executors, execution of their duties shall be decided by majority; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the testator has indicated a contrary intent in his/her will.
Despite the provision of the preceding paragraph, each executor may undertake an act of preservation.
Remuneration of Executor
The family court may determine the remuneration of an executor according to the status of the inherited property and other circumstances; provided that this shall not apply in the case where a testator has specified remuneration in his/her will.
The provisions of paragraphs (2) and (3) of Article 648 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where an executor receives remuneration.
Dismissal and Resignation of Executor
If an executor has failed to perform his/her duties, or if there is any other justifiable reason, an interested party may apply to the family court for the dismissal of that executor.
An executor may resign from his or her duties with the permission of the family court if there is a justifiable reason.
Mandate Provisions to be Applied Mutatis Mutandis
The provisions of Article 654 and Article 655 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case of termination of duties of an executor.
Burden of Expenses Relating to Execution of Will
Expenses relating to the execution of a will shall be borne by the inherited property; provided, however, that legally reserved portion may not be reduced by this.

Revocation and Rescission of Will
Revocation of Will
A testator may at any time revoke a will in whole or in part in compliance with the formalities for a will.
Conflict between Previous and Later Will
If there is a conflict between a previous and later will, the later will shall be deemed as having revoked the previous will with respect to the part that is in conflict.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where a will conflicts with a disposition or other juristic act made while the testator was still alive.
Destruction of Will or Things made the Object of Testamentary Gift
If a testator intentionally destroys a will, this shall be deemed a revocation of the will with respect to the part that has been destroyed. The same shall apply if the testator has intentionally destroyed goods the object of a testamentary gift.
Effect of Will That Has Been Revoked
The effect of a will that has been revoked pursuant to the provisions of Articles 1022 to 1024 inclusive shall not be recovered even if the act of revocation is revoked, rescinded, or invalidated; provided, however, that this shall not apply in the case where the act was the result of fraud or duress.
Prohibition of Waiver of Right to Revocation
A testator may not waive the right to revoke a will.
Rescission of Will concerning Testamentary Gift with Burden
If a person who has received a testamentary gift with burden does not perform the duty imposed thereby, an heir may demand performance of that duty fixing a reasonable period to do so. In this case, if there is no performance within that period, an application may be made to the family court for rescission of the will concerning the testamentary gift with burden.


Legally Reserved Portion
Entitlement and Amount of Legally Reserved Portion
Heirs other than siblings shall receive, as legally reserved portion, an amount equivalent to the ratio prescribed in each of the following items in accordance with the divisions listed therein:
Calculation of Legally Reserved Portion
Total legally reserved portion shall be calculated as the value of any gifts made by the decedent added to the value of the property held by the decedent at the time of commencement of inheritance minus the entire amount of obligations.
The determination of the value of conditional rights or rights of an uncertain duration shall be made in accordance with an evaluation by an appraiser appointed by the family court.
Only a gift made within one year before the commencement of inheritance shall be included in the amount calculated pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article. A gift made before one year prior to commencement shall be included in the amount calculated pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article if it was made with the knowledge of both parties that it would cause harm to a claimant for legally reserved portion.
Claim for Abatement of Gift or Testamentary Gift
A claimant for legally reserved portion, or his/her heir, may claim for abatement of a testamentary gift, or gift referred to in the preceding Article, to the extent necessary to preserve that legally reserved portion.
Partial Abatement of Gifts and Testamentary Gifts of Conditional Rights etc.
In the case where a gift or testamentary gift has as its object a right with conditions attached or a right of uncertain duration, if that gift or testamentary gift is to be partially abated, a claimant for legally reserved portion shall, in accordance with the amount determined by the provision of paragraph (2) of Article 1029, deliver the remainder to the beneficiary or donee immediately.
Order of Abatement of Gifts and Testamentary Gifts
A gift may not be abated until after the abatement of a testamentary gift.
Proportion of Abatement of Testamentary Gift
A testamentary gift shall be abated proportionally according to the value of the object of that testamentary gift; provided, however, that if the testator has indicated a particular intent in his/her will, that intent shall be complied with.
Order of Abatement of Gifts
A later gift shall be abated before an earlier gift.
Return of Fruits of Gift by Beneficiary
A beneficiary, in addition to the property to be returned, shall return the fruits of that property obtained after the day a claim for abatement was made.
Burden of Loss Due to Insolvency of Beneficiary
The burden of loss arising from the insolvency of a beneficiary subject to abatement shall lie with the claimant for legally reserved portion.
Claim for Abatement of Gift with Burden
A claim for abatement may be made regarding a gift with a burden for the amount of the object of that gift minus the amount of the burden.
Act for Value with Inadequate Consideration
An act for value with inadequate consideration shall be deemed a gift if both parties had knowledge that it would prejudice a claimant for legally reserved portion. In this case, if a claimant for legally reserved portion claims for abatement of the gift, he/she shall reimburse the consideration given for the act.
Object of Gift Assigned by Beneficiary etc.
If a beneficiary of gift subject to abatement has assigned the object of a gift to another person, he/she must compensate that amount to a claimant for legally reserved portion; provided, however, that if the person who received the object of the gift had knowledge at the time of assignment that this would prejudice a claimant for legally reserved portion, a claimant for legally reserved portion may claim for abatement of the object of the gift.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case a beneficiary establishes rights with regard to the object of a gift.
Compensation by Value to Claimant for Statutory Reserved Portion
A beneficiary or donee may avoid a duty to refund by compensating a claimant to statutory reserved portion the value of the object of the gift or testamentary gift, to the extent subject to abatement.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the proviso to paragraph (1) of the preceding Article.
Limitation on Period for Claim for Abatement
If a claimant for legally reserved portion, within one year from the time of knowing of commencement of inheritance and the existence of a gift or testamentary gift which may be abated, does not exercise the claim of abatement, it shall be extinguished by prescription. This shall also apply if ten years have passed since the time of commencement of inheritance.
Renunciation of Legally Reserved Portion
Renunciation of legally reserved portion before the commencement of inheritance shall only have effect upon receiving permission from the family court.
The renunciation of legally reserved portion by one joint heir shall have no effect upon the legally reserved portion of another joint heir.
Provisions regarding Heirs per Stirpes and Share in Inheritance to be Applied Mutatis Mutandis
The provisions of paragraph (2) and paragraph (3) of Article 887, Article 900, Article 901, Article 903, and Article 904 shall apply mutatis mutandis to legally reserved portion.
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>V</DOCNO>
Inheritance
General Provisions
Cause of Commencement of Inheritance
Inheritance shall commence upon the death of the decedent.
Place of Commencement of Inheritance
Inheritance shall commence at the place of domicile of the decedent.
Right to Claim for Recovery of Inheritance
If the right to claim for recovery of inheritance is not exercised within five years of the time an heir or his/her legal representative becomes aware of the fact that the inheritance right has been infringed, that right shall be extinguished by prescription. The right shall also be extinguished if twenty years have passed from the time of commencement of inheritance.
Expenses relating to Inherited Property
Expenses relating to inherited property shall be paid out of that property; provided that this shall not apply to expenses resulting from the negligence of an heir.
The expenses of the preceding paragraph are not required to be paid out of property obtained by a claimant to statutory reserved portion through abatement of a gift.


Heir
Unborn Child's Legal Capacity to Hold Rights Relating to Inheritance
In regard to inheritance, an unborn child shall be deemed to have already been born.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply if the child is stillborn.
Right to Inheritance of Child and Heir per Stirpes, etc.
The child of a decedent shall be an heir.
If a decedent's child has died before the commencement of inheritance, or has lost the right to inheritance by application of the provisions of Article 891 or disinheritance, the child of the decedent's child shall be an heir as an heir per stirpes; provided that this shall not apply if the child is not a lineal descendant of the decedent.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where an heir per stirpes has died before the commencement of inheritance, or has lost the right of inheritance as an heir per stirpes by application of the provisions of Article 891, or by disinheritance.
Right of Inheritance of Lineal Ascendant and Sibling
In the case where there is no person to become an heir pursuant to the provisions of Article 887, the following persons shall become heirs in accordance with the following order of rank:
The provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 887 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in item (ii) of the preceding paragraph.
Right of Inheritance of Spouse
The spouse of a decedent shall always be an heir. In this case, if there is a person to become an heir pursuant to the provisions of Article 887 or the preceding Article, the spouse shall be of the same rank as that person.
Causes of Disqualification of Heir
The following persons may not become an heir:
Disinheritance of Presumed Heir
A decedent may make an application to the family court for the disinheritance of a presumed heir (here and below, referring to a person who would otherwise become an heir upon the commencement of inheritance) who has a legally reserved portion if that person has abused or given grave insult to the decedent, or if there has been any other grave misconduct on the part of the presumed heir.
Disinheritance of Presumed Heir by Will
If a decedent has indicated an intention by will to disinherit a presumed heir, the executor of that will shall apply to the family court for disinheritance of the presumed heir without delay after the will has taken effect. In this case, the disinheritance of that presumed heir shall have retroactive effect from the time of the decedent's death.
Rescission of Disinheritance of Presumed Heir
A decedent may at any time make an application to the family court to rescind the disinheritance of a presumed heir.
The provision of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to the rescission of disinheritance of a presumed heir.
Administration of Inherited Property before Ruling for Disinheritance of Presumed Heir Becomes Unappealable
If inheritance has commenced before a ruling has become final and binding after an application for the disinheritance of a presumed heir, or the rescission of that disinheritance, the family court may order any necessary disposition with regard to the administration of inherited property at the request of a relative, an interested party, or a public prosecutor. The same shall apply in the case where a will was made for the disinheritance of a presumed heir.
The provisions of Articles 27 to 29 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where the family court has appointed an administrator of inherited property pursuant to the provisions of the preceding paragraph.


Effect of Inheritance
General Provisions
General Effect of Inheritance
From the time of commencement of inheritance, an heir shall succeed blanket rights and duties attached to the property of the decedent; provided that this shall not apply to rights or duties of the decedent that are purely personal.
Assumption of Rights Relating to Rituals
Despite the provision of the preceding Article, rights to ownership of a genealogy, equipment used in rituals, and any grave, shall be succeeded by the person who custom dictates shall preside over rituals for ancestors; provided that if the decedent designates a person who shall preside over rituals for ancestors, this person shall succeed rights to ownership.
If, in the case referred to in the main text of the preceding paragraph, the custom is not evident, the family court shall determine who shall succeed the rights in that paragraph.
Effect of Joint Inheritance
If there are two or more heirs, the inherited property shall belong to those heirs in co-ownership.
Each joint heir shall succeed the rights and duties of the decedent according to his/her share in inheritance.

Share in Inheritance
Statutory Share in Inheritance
If there are two or more heirs of the same rank, their shares in inheritance shall be determined by the following items:
Statutory Share in Inheritance of Heirs per Stirpes
The share in inheritance of a lineal descendant who becomes an heir pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (2) or paragraph (3) of Article 887 shall be the same as the share that person's lineal ascendant would have received; provided that if there are two or more lineal descendants, their shares in inheritance shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of the preceding Article.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where a child of a sibling becomes an heir pursuant to the provision of paragraph (2) of Article 889.
Designation of Share in Inheritance by Will
Despite the provisions of the preceding two Articles, a decedent may by will determine the share in inheritance of joint heirs, or entrust a third party to determine the share; provided that a decedent or a third party may not violate provisions relating to legally reserved portion.
If a decedent determines, or has a third party determine, the share in inheritance of a single heir or several heirs amongst joint heirs, the share in inheritance of the other joint heir(s) shall be determined pursuant to the provisions of the preceding two Articles.
Share in Inheritance of Heir who has Received Special Benefit
If there is a person from amongst joint heirs who has previously received a testamentary gift, or has received a gift for marriage, adoption, or as capital for livelihood, the total inherited property shall be deemed the value calculated by adding the value of the gift to the value of the property belonging to the decedent at the time of commencement of inheritance and the share in inheritance of that person shall be the remaining amount after deducting the value of that testamentary gift or a gift from the share in inheritance calculated pursuant to the provisions of the preceding three Articles.
If the value of the testamentary gift or gift is equal to, or exceeds, the value of a donee or recipient's share in inheritance, he/she may not receive the share in inheritance.
If the decedent indicates an intention contrary to the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs, that intention shall only have effect to the extent that it does not violate the provisions relating to legally reserved portion.
With regard to the value of the gift referred to in the provisions of the preceding Article, even if, through the conduct of the recipient there the property of the gift is lost, or if there is a fluctuation in its value, the determination of value shall be deemed as the value at the time of commencement of inheritance in its original state.
Contributory Portion
If there is a person from amongst joint heirs who has made a special contribution to the maintenance or increase of the decedent's property through the provision of labor or in the form of property relating to the decedent's business, medical treatment or nursing of the decedent, or other means, the total inherited property shall be deemed the value calculated by deducting the contributory portion as determined by agreement by the joint heirs from the value of the property of the decedent at the time of commencement of inheritance, and that person's share in inheritance shall be the amount of the contribution added to the share in inheritance calculated pursuant to the provisions of Articles 900 to 902 inclusive.
If the agreement of the preceding paragraph is not, or cannot be, settled, the family court shall determine the amount of contributory portion at the request of the person who has contributed referred to in the provision of the preceding paragraph, considering the period of contribution, the means and extent of contribution, the amount of the inherited property, and all other circumstances.
The contributory portion may not exceed the amount calculated by deducting the value of a testamentary gift from the value of the property belonging to the decedent at the time of commencement of inheritance.
The application referred to in paragraph (2) may be made in the case where there has been an application pursuant to the provision of paragraph (2) of Article 907, or in the case where there has been an application pursuant to the provision of Article 910.
Recovery Right of Share of Inheritance
If one joint heir assigns his/her share of inheritance to a third party before a division of the inherited property, any other joint heir may obtain the share through the reimbursement of the value and expenses of that and recover the share in inheritance.
The right of the preceding paragraph shall be exercised within one month.

Division of Inherited Property
Criteria of Division of Inherited Property
Upon the division of inherited property, the type and nature of goods or rights belonging to the inherited property, the age, occupation, mental and physical state, and financial circumstances of each heir, and all other matters, shall be considered.
Agreement or Ruling for Division of Inherited Property etc.
Joint heirs may at any time divide inherited property by agreement except in the case where this is prohibited by the decedent's will pursuant to the provision of the following Article.
If agreement is not, or cannot be, settled between joint heirs regarding division of inherited property, each of the joint heirs may make an application to the family court for a division of the inherited property.
In the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, if there is a special reason, the family court may prohibit the division of the inherited property, in whole or part, for a specified period.
Designation of Form of Division of Inherited Property and Prohibition of Division
A decedent may by will determine the form of division of inherited property, or entrust this to a third party, or prohibit division for a period not exceeding five years from the time of commencement of inheritance.
Effect of Division of Inherited property
Division of inherited property shall have retroactive effect from the time of the commencement of inheritance; provided that this shall not prejudice the rights of a third party.
Claim of Payment for Value of Person Affiliated after Commencement of Inheritance
In the case where a person who becomes an heir through affiliation after the commencement of inheritance intends to apply for a division of the inherited property, if other heirs have already divided the inherited property or made another disposition, he/she shall only have a claim of payment for value.
Mutual Liability to Guarantee Joint Heirs
Each joint heir shall, according to his/her share in inheritance, bear liability to guarantee any other joint heir, just as a seller.
Liability to Guarantee Claim Arising from Division of Inherited Property
Each joint heir shall guarantee, according to his/her share in inheritance, the solvency of any obligor of the inherited property at the time of division regarding claims arising from the division of inherited property.
Each joint heir shall guarantee the solvency of any obligor of the inherited property at the time for performance regarding a claim that is either not yet due or has a condition precedent.
Share of Liability to Guarantee Insolvent Joint Heir
If there is an insolvent joint heir who is liable to guarantee other joint heirs, the portion of the liability which the insolvent joint heir is to bear shall be apportioned amongst other joint heirs with a right to reimbursement, and other solvent joint heirs shall contribute to the portion unable to be reimbursed according to the share in inheritance of each; provided that if there is negligence on the part of the person who seeks reimbursement, he/she may not make a claim against other another joint heir to contribute.
Determination of Liability to Guarantee by Will
If a decedent has expressed a different intent by will, the provisions of the preceding three Articles shall not apply.


Acceptance and Renunciation of Inheritance
General Provisions
Period for Acceptance or Renunciation of Inheritance
An heir shall give unconditional or qualified acceptance, or renunciation, regarding inheritance within three months of the time he/she has knowledge that there has been a commencement of inheritance for him/her; provided that this period may be extended by the family court at the request of an interested party or a public prosecutor.
An heir may investigate inherited property before making an acceptance or renunciation of inheritance.
If an heir dies without having made acceptance or renunciation of inheritance, the period of paragraph (1) of the preceding Article shall be calculated from the time that person's heir comes to know of the commencement of inheritance for himself/herself.
If an heir is a minor or an adult ward, the period in paragraph (1) of Article 915 shall be calculated from the time that legal representative comes to know of the commencement of inheritance for the minor or adult ward.
Administration of Inherited Property
An heir shall administer inherited property with the same care he/she would exercise over his/her own property; provided that this shall not apply if he/she has accepted or renounced the inheritance.
The family court may at any time order any necessary disposition for the preservation of inherited property at the request of an interested party or a public prosecutor.
The provisions of Articles 27 to 29 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where the family court has appointed an administrator manager of inherited property pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph.
Revocation and Rescission of Acceptance and Renunciation of Inheritance
Acceptance or renunciation of inheritance may not be revoked even within the period referred to in paragraph (1) of Article 915.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not prevent the rescission of acceptance or renunciation of inheritance made pursuant to the provisions of Part 1 (General Provisions) and Part 4 (Relatives).
The right of rescission in the preceding paragraph shall be extinguished by prescription if not exercised within six months of the time ratification becomes possible. The right of rescission in the preceding paragraph shall be extinguished if ten years have passed since the time of acceptance or renunciation of inheritance.
A person who intends to rescind qualified acceptance or renunciation of inheritance pursuant to the provision of paragraph (2) shall provide a statement to that effect to the family court.

Acceptance of Inheritance
Unconditional Acceptance
Effect of Unconditional Acceptance
If an heir makes unconditional acceptance, he/she shall inherit the rights and duties of the decedent without limitation.
Statutory Unconditional Acceptance
An heir shall be deemed to have made unconditional acceptance in the following cases:
Qualified Acceptance
Qualified Acceptance
An heir may accept inheritance reserving to perform the obligation or testamentary gift of the decedent only within the extent of the property obtained by inheritance.
Qualified Acceptance of Joint Heirs
If there are two or more heirs, qualified acceptance may only be made if all members of the joint heirs make qualified acceptance jointly.
Form of Qualified Acceptance
If an heir intends to make qualified acceptance, he/she shall prepare an inventory of the inherited property and submit this to the family court with a statement to that effect within the period of paragraph (1) of Article 915.
Rights and Duties upon Qualified Acceptance
If an heir makes qualified acceptance, the rights and duties that person has towards the decedent shall be deemed not to have been extinguished.
Administration by Person who has Made Qualified Acceptance
A person who has made qualified acceptance shall continue administration of inherited property with the same care he/she would exercise over his/her own property.
Article 645, Article 646, paragraph (1) and paragraph (2) of Article 650, paragraph (2) and paragraph (3) of Article 918 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Public Notification and Notice to Inheritance Obligees and Donees
A person who makes qualified acceptance shall, within five days of making that qualified acceptance, make public notification to all inheritance obligees (here and below, an obligee with a claim towards the inherited property) and donees to the effect that qualified acceptance has been made and that filing of any claim should be made within a specified period. In this case, that period shall be not less than two months.
In the public notification in the preceding paragraph, it shall be prescribed that inheritance obliges and donees who failed to file should be precluded from the payment; provided, however, that a successor who makes qualified acceptance may not preclude known inheritance obliges and donees.
a successor who makes qualified acceptance shall demand each of known inheritance obliges and donees the filing.
The public notice in paragraph (1) shall be made on the official gazette.
Refusal of Performance before Expiration of Public Notification Period
A person who has made qualified acceptance may refuse to make performance to an inheritance obligee or donee before the expiration of the notification period of paragraph (1) of the preceding Article.
Performance after Expiration of Public Notification Period
After the expiration of the period in paragraph (1) of Article 927, a person who has made qualified acceptance shall use the inherited property to make performance to inheritance obligees who have made the application of the same paragraph within the period prescribed, and any other known inheritance obligees, proportionally according to the amount of each claim; provided that this may not prejudice the rights of an obligee with priority rights.
Performance of Obligation etc. Not Yet Due
A person who has made qualified acceptance must make performance even of a claim which is not yet due in accordance with the provision of the preceding Article.
Conditional claims and claims of indefinite duration shall be performed in accordance with an evaluation by an appraiser appointed by the family court.
Performance to Donees
A person who has made qualified acceptance may not make performance to a donee unless each of the inheritance obligees has been paid in accordance with the provisions of the preceding two Articles.
Auction of Inherited Property for Performance of Obligation
If it is necessary to sell inherited property in order to perform in accordance with the provisions of the preceding three Articles, a person who has made qualified acceptance shall put that property to auction; provided that this auction may be averted by paying the entire or partial value of the inherited property in accordance with an evaluation by an appraiser appointed by the family court.
Participation of Inheritance Obligees and Donees in Evaluation Proceedings
Inheritance obligees and donees may, by their own expense, participate in an auction or appraisal of inherited property. In this case, the provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 260 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Liability for Unfair Performance etc. of Person who has Made Qualified Acceptance
If a person who has made qualified acceptance fails to make the public notification or notice referred to in Article 927, or has made performance to an inheritance obligee or donee within the period of paragraph (1) of the same Article thereby precluding performance to any other inheritance obligee or donee, that person shall be liable to compensate for damages arising from this. If he/she has made performance that violates the provisions of Articles 929 to 931 inclusive, he/she shall be liable to compensate for damages arising from this.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not prevent a claim for damages against an inheritance obligee or donee who has accepted unfair performance with knowledge by another inheritance obligee or donee.
The provision of Article 724 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases referred to in the preceding two paragraphs.
Inheritance Obligees or Donees who have not Made Application within Period of Public Notification
An inheritance obligee or donee who fails to make the application referred to in paragraph (1) of Article 927 within the period prescribed, and was unknown to the person who has made qualified acceptance, may only exercise his/her rights over the residual assets; provided that this shall not apply to persons who have a security over specific inherited property.
Administration of Inherited Property where Two or more Heirs
In the case where there are two or more heirs, the family court shall appoint an administrator of the inherited property from amongst the heirs.
The administrator of the inherited property of the preceding paragraph shall undertake all necessary acts to administer the inherited property and perform any obligation on behalf of the heirs.
The provisions of Article 926 to 935 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to an administrator of the inherited property of paragraph (1). In this case, 'within five days of making that qualified acceptance' in paragraph (1) of Article 927 shall be read as 'within ten days of the appointment of an administrator of the inherited property'.
Inheritance Obligees Where There is Cause for Statutory Unconditional Acceptance
If there is a cause listed in item (i) or item (iii) of Article 921 relating to one or several joint heirs who have made qualified acceptance, an inheritance obligee may exercise his/her rights over the portion of his/her claim not satisfied by the inherited property against those joint heirs according to the share in inheritance of each.

Renunciation of Inheritance
Method of Renunciation of Inheritance
A person who intends to renounce inheritance shall make a statement to that effect to the family court.
Effect of Renunciation of Inheritance
A person who has renounced inheritance shall be deemed as not originally having been an heir to the inheritance.
Administration by Person who has Renounced Inheritance
A person who has renounced inheritance shall continue the administration of inherited property with the same care he/she would exercise over his/her own property until the person who has become an heir by that renunciation has commenced administration of the inherited property.
Article 645, Article 646, paragraphs (1) and (2) of Article 650, paragraphs (2) and paragraph (3) of Article 918 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.


Separation of Property
Separation of Property by Claim of Inheritance Obligees or Donees
An inheritance obligee or a donee may make an application to the family court for a separation of inheritance property from the property of an heir within three months of the time of commencement of inheritance. The application may be filed even after that period has elapsed if the inherited property has not been mixed with the heir's own property.
If the family court has made a ruling for separation of property pursuant to the application of the preceding paragraph, the applicant shall give public notice within five days to the effect that an order for separation of property has been made and that applications for entry into distribution proceedings should be made within a specified period. In this case, that period shall be not less than two months.
The public notice of the provisions of the preceding paragraph shall be listed in the official gazette.
Effect of Separation of Property
A person who has made an application for separation of property or a person who has applied for entry into distribution proceedings pursuant to the provisions of paragraph (2) of the preceding Article shall receive performance with priority over the obligees of an heir regarding the inherited property.
Administration of Inherited Property after Claim for Separation of Property
If an application for separation of property is made, the family court may order any necessary disposition for the administration of the inherited property.
The provisions of Articles 27 to 29 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where the family court appoints an administrator pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph.
Administration by Heir after Application for Separation of Property
Even after an heir has made unconditional acceptance, if there has been an application for separation of property, he/she shall administer the inherited property with the same care he/she would exercise over his/her own property; provided that this shall not apply if the family court has appointed an administrator of the inherited property.
The provisions of Articles 645 to 647 inclusive and paragraphs (1) and (2) of Article 650 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Requirement of Perfection, against Third Party regarding Real Estate in the Case of Separation of Property
A separation of property regarding real estate may not be asserted against a third party unless the separation is registered.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Provisions regarding Extension of Security Interest to the Proceeds of Collateral
The provisions of Article 304 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case of separation of property.
Performance to Inheritance Obligees and Donees
Before the expiration of the period in paragraphs (1) and (2) of Article 941, an heir may refuse to make performance to an inheritance obligee or donee.
If an application for separation of property has been made, an heir shall use the inherited property to make performance to any inheritance obligee or donee who has made an application for separation of property or entry into distribution proceedings proportionally according to the amount of each claim, after the expiration of the period of paragraph (2) of Article 941; provided however, that this may not prejudice the rights of an obligee with priority rights.
The provisions of Articles 930 to 934 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Performance from Heir's Own Property
A person who has made an application for separation of property or a person who has applied for entry into distribution proceedings may exercise his/her rights against an heir's own property only in the case where he/she was not able to receive performance in full from the inherited property. In this case, this person may receive performance with priority over the obligees of an heir.
Prevention etc. of Application for Separation of Property
An heir may use his/her own property to make performance to an inheritance obligee or donee, or provide reasonable security, and thereby prevent an application for separation of property or have its effect extinguished; provided that this shall not apply if an obligee of the heir expresses an objection and can prove that he/she would receive damage from this.
Separation of Property by Application of Obligee of Heir
While an heir may make qualified acceptance, or while the inherited property has not been mixed with the heir's own property, an obligee of the heir may make an application to the family court for a separation of property.
The provisions of Article 304, Article 925, Articles 927 to 934 inclusive, Articles 943 to 945 inclusive, and Article 948 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph; provided, however, that the public notification and notice of Article 927 shall be made by an obligee who has made an application for separation of property.


Nonexistence of Heir
Formation of Juridical Person for Inherited Property
If it is not evident whether an heir exists, an estate that would be inherited shall be as a juridical person.
Appointment of Administrator of Inherited Property
In the case referred to in the preceding Article, the family court shall appoint an administrator of inherited property at the request of an interested party or a public prosecutor.
If an administrator of inherited property has been appointed pursuant to the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the family court shall give public notice of this without delay.
Provisions Relating to Administrator of Absentee's Property to be Applied Mutatis Mutandis
The provisions of Articles 27 to 29 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the administrator of inherited property referred to in paragraph (1) of the preceding Article (in this Chapter, 'administrator of inherited property').
Reporting by Administrator of Inherited Property
If there is an application by an inheritance obligee or donee, an administrator of inherited property shall report the status of the inherited property to the person who has made the application.
Non-formation of Juridical Person for Inherited Property
If it has become evident that there is an heir, the juridical person of Article 951 shall be deemed not to have been formed; provided, however, that this shall not prevent the effect of acts done by an administrator of inherited property within the administrator's authority.
Extinguishment of Authority of Representation of Administrator of Inherited Property
The authority of representation of an administrator of inherited property shall be extinguished from the time that an heir accepts inheritance.
In the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, the administrator of inherited property shall make an account of profit and loss to the heir without delay.
Performance to Inheritance Obligees and Donees
If the existence of an heir has not become evident within two months of the public notice of paragraph (2) of Article 952, an administrator of inherited property shall, without delay, give public notice to all inheritance obligees and donees to the effect that a claim for performance should be made within a specified period. In this case, the period shall be not less than two months.
The provisions of paragraphs (2) to (4) inclusive of Article 927 and Articles 928 to 935 (excluding the proviso to Article 932) shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Public Notice of Search for Heir
If, after the expiration of the period in paragraph (1) of the preceding Article, it is still not evident whether an heir exists, the family court shall, at the request of an administrator of inherited property or a public prosecutor, give public notice to the effect that if there is an heir, he/she should assert his/her right within a fixed period. In this case, the period shall be not less than six months.
Case where No Person Claims a Right
If there is no person who asserts a right as an heir within the period of the preceding Article, an heir, or any obligee or donee unknown to the administrator of inherited property, may not exercise his/her right.
Distribution of Inherited Property to Person with Special Connection
In the case referred to in the preceding Article, the family court may, if it finds it reasonable, at the request of a person who shared a livelihood with the decedent, a person who contributed to the medical treatment and nursing of the decedent, or any other person who had a special connection with the decedent, grant such person the remaining amount of the inherited property after liquidation, in whole or in part.
The application of the preceding paragraph must be made within three months of the expiration of the period in Article 958.
Residual Assets to Belong to National Treasury
Inherited property that has not been disposed of pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article shall belong to the National Treasury. In this case, the provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 956 shall apply mutatis mutandis.


Wills
General Provisions
Formalities for Will
No will shall take effect unless made in accordance with the formalities provided in this Code.
Capacity to Make Will
Any person who has attained 15 years of age may make a will.
The provisions of Article 5, Article 9, Article 13 and Article 17 shall not apply to a will.
At the time of making a will, a testator shall have the capacity to do so.
Comprehensive and Specific Testamentary Gifts
A testator may make a disposition of his/her property, in whole or in part, comprehensive or specific title(s); provided that this may not violate provisions regarding legally reserved portion.
Provisions Relating to Heirs to be Applied Mutatis Mutandis
The provisions of Article 886 and Article 891 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a testamentary donee.
Limitations on Will of Person under Guardianship
If a person under guardianship makes a will to the benefit of a guardian or the guardian's spouse or lineal relative before the completion of a profit and loss account for guardianship, that will shall be void.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply in the case where a lineal relative, spouse, or sibling of the ward is a guardian.
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>III</DOCNO>
Claims
General Provisions
Subject of Claim
Subject of Claim
Even a matter that cannot be given an estimated monetary value may be the subject of a claim.
Duty of Care in cases of Delivery of Specified Things
If the subject of a claim is the delivery of any specified things, the obligor must take custody of such property with due care of a prudent manager until the completion of such delivery.
Fungible Claim
In cases the subject of the claim is specified only with reference to a type and if the quality of such property cannot be identified due to the nature of the juristic act or intention of the relevant party(ies), the obligor must deliver the property of intermediate quality.
In the case set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the obligor has completed the acts necessary to deliver the Thing, or has identified the Thing he/she is to deliver with the consent of the obligee, such Thing shall thenceforth constitute the subject of the claim.
Monetary Claim
If the subject of the claim is money, the obligor may, at his/her choice, make the payment in currency of any kind; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the delivery of specific kind of currency is identified as the subject of the claim.
If the specific kind of currency that is the subject of the claim is no longer in mandatory circulation at the time of the payment, the obligor must make payment in other currency.
The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases where the delivery of the currency of a foreign state is the subject of the claim.
When the amount of the claim is specified in the currency of a foreign state, the obligor may make the payment in the legal currency of Japan using the foreign exchange rate current in the place of the performance.
Statutory Interest Rate
Unless the parties otherwise manifest their intention with respect to a claim which bears interest, the rate of such interest shall be 5% per annum.
Incorporation of Interest into Principal
In cases the payment of interest corresponding to one year or more is delayed, and if the obligor does not pay such interest notwithstanding the demand by the obligee, the obligee may incorporate such interest into the principal.
Attribution of Right of Choice in cases of Alternative Obligation
If the subject of the claim is to be identified by way of choice among more than one performance, the right to make the choice shall vest in the obligor.
Exercise of Right of Choice
The right of choice under the preceding Article shall be exercised by manifesting the intention to the counterparty.
The manifestation of intention set forth in the preceding paragraph may not be revoked without the acknowledgment of the counterparty.
Transfer of Right of Choice
In cases a claim is due and, notwithstanding a demand by the counterparty stipulating a reasonable period of time, the party who holds the right of choice does not exercise the right within such period of time, the right of choice shall be transferred to the counterparty.
Right of Choice of Third Party
In cases a third party holds the right of choice, such choice shall be made by manifesting its intention to either the obligee or the obligor.
In the case prescribed in the preceding paragraph, if the third party is unable to make the choice or has no intention to make the choice, the right of choice shall be transferred to the obligor.
Identification of Alternative Obligation due to Impossibility
If any performance which is included in the subject of a claim is impossible from the beginning, or later becomes impossible, the claim shall exist to the extent of the performance which still remains.
If any performance has become impossible due to the negligence of any party who does not have any right of choice, the provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply.
Effect of Choice
The choice shall become effective retroactively as of the time of the accrual of the claim; provided, however that this shall not prejudice the rights of a third party.

Effect of Claims
Responsibility for Default
Time for Performance and Delay in Performance
If any specified due date is assigned to the performance of an obligation, the obligor shall be responsible for the delay on and after the time of the arrival of such time limit.
If any unspecified due date is assigned to the performance of a claim, the obligor shall be responsible for the delay on and after the time when he/she becomes aware of the arrival of such time limit.
If no time limit is assigned to the performance of an obligation, the obligor shall be responsible for the delay on and after the time he/she receives the request for performance.
Obligee's Delay in Acceptance
If the obligee refuses, or is unable, to accept the tender of the performance of any obligation, the relevant obligee shall be responsible for the delay on and after the time of the tender of the performance.
Enforcement of Performance
If an obligor voluntarily fails to perform any obligation, the obligee may request the enforcement of specific performance from the court; provided, however, that, this shall not apply where the nature of the obligation does not permit such enforcement.
In cases the nature of the obligation does not permit the enforcement of the specific performance, if it is an obligation for an act, the obligee may request the court to cause a third party to perform such act at the expense of the obligor; provided, however, that with respect to any obligation for any juristic act, the manifestation of intention of the obligor may be achieved by a judgment.
With respect to any obligation for an inaction, a request may be made to the court at the expense of the obligor seeking the removal of the outcome of the action performed by the obligor, or an appropriate ruling against any future action.
The provisions of the preceding three paragraphs shall not preclude demanding damages.
Damages due to Default
If an obligor fails to perform consistent with the purpose of its obligation, the obligee shall be entitled to demand damages arising from such failure. The same shall apply in cases it has become impossible to perform due to reasons attributable to the obligor.
Scope of Damages
The purpose of the demand for the damages for failure to perform an obligation shall be to demand the compensation for damages which would ordinarily arise from such failure.
The obligee may also demand the compensation for damages which arise from any special circumstances if the party did foresee, or should have foreseen, such circumstances.
Method of Compensation for Damages
Unless other intention is manifested, the amount of the damages shall be determined with reference to monetary value.
Comparative Negligence
If the obligee is negligent regarding the failure of performance of the obligation, the court shall determine the liability for damages and the amount thereof by taking such elements into consideration.
Special Provisions for Monetary Debt
The amount of the damages for failure to perform any obligation for the delivery of any money shall be determined with reference to the statutory interest rate; provided, however, that, in cases the agreed interest rate exceeds the statutory interest rate, the agreed interest rate shall prevail.
The obligee shall not be required to prove his/her damages with respect to the damages set forth in the preceding paragraph.
The obligor may not raise the defense of force majeure with respect to the damages referred to in paragraph 1.
Liquidated Damages
The parties may agree on the amount of the liquidated damages with respect to the failure to perform the obligation. In such case, the court may not increase or decrease the amount thereof.
The liquidated damages shall not preclude the demand for performance or the exercise of the cancellation right.
Any penalty is presumed to constitute liquidated damages.
The provisions of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases where the parties agree in advance to allocate anything other than money to the compensation for damages.
Subrogation for Damages
If an obligee receives the full value of any Thing or right which is the subject of the claim as the compensation for damages, the obligor shall be subrogated to the creditor in relation to such property or right by operation of law.
Obligee's Subrogation Right and Obligee's Right to Demand Rescission of Fraudulent Act
Obligee's Subrogation Right
An obligee may exercise the right vested in the obligor in order to preserve his/her own claim; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to rights which are exclusive and personal to the obligor.
Until exercised by way of subrogation admitted in a judicial proceeding, the obligee may not exercise the right set forth in the preceding paragraph unless and until his/her claim has become due; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to any act of preservation.
Obligee's Right to Demand the Rescission of Fraudulent Act
An obligee may demand the court to rescind any juristic act which an obligor commits knowing that it will prejudice the obligee; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where any person who benefits from such act, or any person who succeeds to such benefit, did not know, at the time of such act or succession, the fact that the obligee is to be prejudiced.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply to a juristic act with a subject other than property rights.
Effect of Rescission of Fraudulent Act
The rescission pursuant to the provision of the preceding Article shall have an effect for the benefit of all obligees.
Limitation Period of Obligee's Right to Rescind Fraudulent Act
The right to rescind pursuant to the provision of Article 424 shall be extinguished by operation of prescription if not exercised within two years from the time that the obligee acquired knowledge of the cause of the rescission. The same shall apply if twenty years pass from the time of the act.

Claims and Obligations of Multiple-Parties
General Provisions
Divisible Claims and Divisible Obligations
In cases there are more than one obligee or obligor, unless any other intention is manifested, each obligee or each obligor shall have the equally proportionate rights or obligations.
Indivisible Claims and Indivisible Obligations
Indivisible Claim
In cases the subject of a claim is indivisible by its nature or due to the manifestation of intention of the parties involved, if there are more than one obligees, each obligee may demand the performance for the benefit of all obligees, and the relevant obligor may tender its performance to each obligee for the benefit of all obligees. respect to One Indivisible Obligee)
Even in cases where there is a novation or release between one indivisible obligee and the obligor, other indivisible obligee(s) may request the obligor to tender the entire performance. In such cases, the benefit which would have been allocated to the above-mentioned one indivisible obligee if he/she did not lose his/her right must be reimbursed to the relevant obligor.
Other than as prescribed in the preceding paragraph, any act of one indivisible obligee, or any circumstance which arises with respect to one indivisible obligee shall not have any effect on the other indivisible obligee(s).
Indivisible Obligation
The provisions of the preceding Article, and the provisions of the following Subsection III (Joint and Several Obligation)(excluding the provisions of Articles 434 to 440 inclusive) shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases where more than one person bears any indivisible obligation.
Changing into Divisible Claims or Divisible Obligations
If any indivisible claim becomes a divisible claim, each obligee may request the performance only to the extent of such portion of the claim on which he/she has his/her own right, and if any indivisible obligation becomes a divisible obligation, each obligor shall bear his/her responsibility only to the extent of the portion of the obligation which he/she bears.
Joint and Several Obligations
Request for Performance
If more than one person bears a joint and several obligation, the obligee may request one of the joint and several obligors, or all of such joint and several obligors, simultaneously or successively, to perform the obligation, in whole or in part.
Invalidity of Juristic Act with respect to One Joint and Several Obligor
Even if there are any grounds for the voidance or rescission of a juristic act with respect to only one joint and several obligor, the validity of the obligation(s) of other joint and several obligor(s) shall not be impaired.
Request for Performance to One Joint and Several Obligor
A request for performance made to one joint and several obligor shall also be effective with respect to other joint and several obligor(s).
Novation with One Joint and Several Obligor
If there is any novation between one joint and several obligor and the obligee, the claim shall be extinguished for the benefit of all joint and several obligors.
Setoffs by One Joint and Several Obligor
In cases one joint and several obligor has a claim vis-a-vis the obligee, if such joint and several obligor invokes a setoff, the claim shall be extinguished for the benefit of all joint and several obligors.
So long as the joint and several obligor who has the claim set forth in the preceding paragraph does not invoke the set-off, other joint and several obligor(s) may invoke the set-off solely to the extent of the portion of the obligation which is borne by such joint and several obligor.
Releases of One Joint and Several Obligor
A release of an obligation effected for one joint and several obligor shall also be effective for the benefit of other joint and several obligor(s) solely to the extent of the portion of the obligation which is borne by such joint and several obligor.
Merger with One Joint and Several Obligor
If there is any merger between one joint and several obligor and the relevant obligee, it is deemed that such joint and several obligor has performed his/her obligation.
Completion of Prescription with respect to One Joint and Several Obligor
If the prescription is completed with respect to one joint and several obligor, the other joint and several obligors also shall be relieved of liability to the extent of the portion of the obligation which is borne by such joint and several obligor.
Principle of Relative Effect
Except as set forth in Articles 434 to the preceding Article inclusive, any circumstance which arises with respect to one joint and several obligor shall be void vis-a-vis other joint and several obligor(s).
Commencement of Bankruptcy Procedures for Joint and Several Obligors
When some or all of the joint and several obligors have become subject to the ruling of the commencement of bankruptcy procedures, the obligee may participate in the distribution of each bankruptcy estate with respect to the entire amount of his/her claim.
Right to Obtain Reimbursement among Joint and Several Obligors
If one joint and several obligor performs the obligation, or has otherwise acquired any common discharge in exchange for his/her own property, such joint and several obligor shall have right to obtain reimbursement from other joint and several obligors to the extent of the respective portion of the obligations which is borne by each of other joint and several obligors.
The reimbursement pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph shall include the compensation of the statutory interest which accrue on or after the day of the performance of the obligation or other discharge, any unavoidable expenses, and other damages. Notice)
When one joint and several obligor performs his/her obligation or has otherwise acquired any common discharge in exchange for his/her own property without giving to the other joint and several obligor(s) a notice that there was the request for the performance from the relevant obligee, if any of the other joint and several obligor(s) has any defense vis-a-vis the obligee, such joint and several obligor may raise such defense vis-a-vis the joint and several obligor who acquired the discharge to the extent of the portion of the obligation which is borne by himself/herself. In such case, if any defense vis-a-vis the joint and several obligor who acquired the discharge is raised on the grounds of set-off, the negligent joint and several obligor may request the relevant obligee to perform the obligation which should have been extinguished due to set-off.
When one joint and several obligor performs the obligation or has otherwise acquired any common discharge in exchange for his/her own property and has failed to give notice of such fact to other joint and several obligor(s), and as a result of such failure, any other joint and several obligor acquires discharge by performing the obligation or otherwise in exchange for an act performed for consideration without knowledge, the joint and several obligor who was so discharged shall be entitled to regard his/her act to perform or other act to acquire the discharge as effective. Resources for Reimbursement)
If there is any person among the joint and several obligors who does not have the sufficient financial resources to make the reimbursement, the portion that cannot be reimbursed shall be borne among the person(s) who demand(s) the reimbursement and other person(s) who has/have the financial resources, in proportion to the respective portion which is borne by each of such persons; provided, however, that the person who requests the reimbursement may not demand other joint and several obligor(s) to bear the burden if he/she is negligent. Burden of Person who does not have Sufficient Financial Resources to Pay)
In cases any one joint and several obligor is released from the joint and several obligation, if there is any person among other joint and several obligors who does not have the sufficient financial resources to pay the obligation, the obligee shall bear such portion of the obligation which may not be performed by such person without sufficient financial resources as should have been borne by the person who was released from the joint and several obligation.
Guarantee Obligation
Guarantee Obligation
Responsibility of Guarantor
A guarantor shall have the responsibility to perform the obligation of the principal obligor when the latter fails to perform such obligation.
No contract of guarantee shall be effective unless it is made in writing.
If a contract of guarantee is concluded by electromagnetic record means unrecognizable by natural sensory functions that is for computer data-processing use) which records the contents thereof, the contract of guarantee is deemed to be made in writing, and the provision of the preceding paragraph shall apply.
Scope of Guarantee Obligation
The guarantee obligation shall include interest, penalty and compensation for damages in connection with the principal obligation, and all other charges incidental to such obligation.
A guarantor may stipulate the amount of penalty or compensation for damages with regard to his/her own guarantee obligation only. Obligor)
If the burden of a guarantor is more onerous than that of the principal obligor as to either its subject or its terms, it shall be reduced to the extent of the principal obligation.
Guarantee of Rescindable Obligation
If a guarantor, who has guaranteed an obligation which may be rescinded by reason of the principal obligor's limited capacity to act, was aware, at the time of entering into a contract guarantee, of the cause for its voidability, such guarantor shall be presumed to have assumed an independent obligation of the same subject in the event of nonperformance by the principal obligor or rescission of the obligation.
Requirements for Guarantor
Where an obligor has the obligation to furnish a guarantor, such guarantor must:
If the guarantor ceases to meet the requirement set forth in item (ii) of the preceding paragraph, the obligee may demand that some other person meeting the requirements listed in any item of such paragraph be substituted for such guarantor.
The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall not apply in the case the obligee has designated the guarantor.
Providing Other Security
If the obligor is unable to furnish a guarantor meeting the requirements listed in any item of paragraph 1 of the preceding Article, he/she may furnish other security in lieu thereof.
Defense of Demand
If an obligee has demanded performance of an obligation from the guarantor, the guarantor may demand the obligee to demand performance of the principal obligor first; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the principal obligor has received a ruling for the commencement of bankruptcy procedures or where his/her whereabouts are unknown.
Defense of Reference
Even after the obligee has made a demand to the principal obligor in accordance with the provision of the preceding Article, the obligee must first execute on the property of the principal obligor if the guarantor has proved that the principal obligor has the financial resource to pay his/her obligation and that the execution would be easily performed.
Special Provisions for Joint and Several Guarantee
If a guarantor has assumed an obligation jointly and severally with the principal obligor, the guarantor shall not have the rights set forth in the preceding two Articles.
Effect of Defense of Demand and Defense of Reference
Where demand has been made or proof has been given by a guarantor pursuant to the provisions of Article 452 or Article 453, if the obligee fails to demand or to levy execution and is subsequently unable to obtain full performance from the principal obligor, the guarantor shall be relieved of liability to the extent that the obligee would have received performance if the obligee had immediately demanded or levied execution.
Cases where More Than One Guarantor Exists
Where there is more than one guarantor for a single obligation, the provision of Article 427 shall apply even if they have assumed their obligations by separate acts.
Effect of Circumstance which Arises with respect to the Principal Obligor
The nullification of prescription by operation of a demand vis-a-vis the principal obligor or on any other grounds shall also be effective vis-a-vis the guarantor.
A guarantor may raise a defense vis-a-vis the obligee by setting off any claim which the principal obligor may have vis-a-vis the obligee. Liable Guarantor)
The provisions of Articles 434 to 440 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases where the principal obligor assumes an obligation jointly and severally with the guarantor. Obligor)
In cases where a guarantor has given a guarantee as entrusted by the principal obligor, if he/she has, without negligence, had a judgment ordering him/her to perform the obligation to the obligee, or has performed the obligation on behalf of the principal obligor, or has otherwise in exchange for his/her own property performed any other act intended to cause the obligation to be extinguished, such guarantor shall have a right to obtain reimbursement from the principal obligor.
The provision of paragraph 2 of Article 442 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph.
Entrusted Guarantor's Right to Obtain Reimbursement in Advance
In cases where a guarantor has given a guarantee as entrusted by the principal obligor, the guarantor may exercise in advance his/her right to obtain reimbursement vis-a-vis the principal obligor if: bankruptcy procedures, and the obligee does not participate in the distribution of the bankruptcy estate; granted by the obligee to the principal obligor after the conclusion of the contract of guarantee may be raised as a defense vis-a-vis the guarantor; and guarantee in the cases where the time for performing the obligation is uncertain and even its maximum duration cannot be ascertained.
Cases where Principal Obligor Reimburses Guarantor
In cases where a principal obligor reimburses a guarantor pursuant to the provisions of the preceding two Articles, the principal obligor may demand the guarantor to provide security or to obtain the discharge of the principal obligor until and unless the obligee has received the full satisfaction of the entire obligation.
In the case prescribed in the preceding paragraph, the principal obligor may be relieved of liability for reimbursement by making a deposit with an official depository, by providing security, or by procuring the discharge of the liabilities of the guarantor. Obligor)
If a person, who has become a guarantor without the entrustment of the principal obligor, has performed the obligation or has otherwise in exchange for his/her own property procured the release from liability of the principal obligor, the principal obligor must reimburse the guarantor to the extent that the principal obligor was enriched at the time of such performance of the obligation.
A person who has become a guarantor against the will of the principal obligor shall have the right to obtain reimbursement only to the extent that the principal obligor is actually enriched. In such case, if the principal obligor asserts that he/she had, prior to the day of the demand for reimbursement, grounds for set-off against the obligee, the guarantor may demand that the obligee perform the obligation which would have been extinguished by operation of such set-off.
Limitation on Reimbursement for Guarantor who Failed to give Notice
The provisions of Article 443 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a guarantor.
In cases where a guarantor has become a guarantor as entrusted by the principal obligor, if he/she performed the obligation or otherwise in exchange for his/her own property performed any act to cause the obligation to be extinguished without knowledge, the provision of Article 443 shall apply mutatis mutandis also with respect to the principal obligor. Obligation or Indivisible Obligation)
A person who has become a guarantor for one of the jointly and several obligors or for one of the indivisible obligors shall have the right to obtain reimbursement from the other obligors only to the extent of such portion of the obligation which he/she bears.
Right of Joint Guarantors to Obtain Reimbursement for One Obligation
Where there are several guarantors, if one guarantor has paid the entire amount of the obligation or any amount exceeding the portion which is borne by such guarantor because the principal obligation is indivisible, or because there is a special provision that each guarantor should pay the entire amount, the provisions of Articles 442 to 444 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Except in cases provided in the preceding paragraph, if one of the guarantors who are not jointly and severally liable has paid the entire amount or any amount exceeding the portion to be borne by that guarantor, the provisions of Article 462 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Guarantee Obligation
Liability of Guarantor of Contract for Revolving Guarantee on Loans
A guarantor to a contract of guarantee the principal obligation of which is one or more unidentified obligations within a certain specified scope (hereinafter referred to as a "contract for revolving guarantee") whereby the scope of such obligation includes any obligation which is incurred as a result of the transaction of lending money or accepting discount of a negotiable instrument (hereinafter referred to as an "loan obligation")(excluding any contract in which the guarantor is a juridical person, hereinafter referred to as a "contract for revolving guarantee on loans") shall be liable for the satisfaction of the amount of the principal of the relevant principal obligation, interest, any penalty and damages in connection with such principal obligation, and all other amounts incidental to such obligation, as well as the amount of any penalty and damages which are agreed on with regard to such guarantee obligation, which liability shall be limited in aggregate, however, to a certain maximum amount which pertains to all of the above-mentioned amounts.
A contract for revolving guarantee on loans shall not be effective unless the maximum amount set forth in the preceding paragraph is stipulated.
The provisions of paragraph 2 and paragraph 3 of Article 446 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the stipulation of a maximum amount in a contract for revolving guarantee on loans provided in paragraph 1.
Principal Determination Date for Contract for Revolving Guarantee on Loans
In the cases where a contract for revolving guarantee on loans provides the date on which the principal of the principal obligation should be determined (hereinafter referred to as the "principal determination date"), if it is provided that such principal determination date shall fall on any day on and or after the day on which five years have elapsed after the day of the conclusion of the relevant contract for the revolving guarantee on loans, such provision for the principal determination date shall not be effective.
In the cases where a contract for revolving guarantee on loans does not provide a principal determination date (including cases where the provision on the principal determination date is not effective pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph), the principal determination date thereof shall fall on the day on which three years have elapsed after the day of the conclusion of the relevant contract for revolving guarantee on loans.
In the cases where any change of the principal determination date provided in a contract for revolving guarantee on loans is to be effected, if the principal determination date as changed falls on a day on and or after the day on which five years have elapsed after the day of such change, such change of the principal determination date shall not be effective; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the change of the principal determination date is effected within two months immediately preceding the principal determination date, and the principal determination date as changed falls on a day within five years from the original principal determination date.
The provisions of paragraph 2 and paragraph 3 of Article 446 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the provisions of a principal determination date set forth in a contract for revolving guarantee on loans and a change thereof determination date shall fall on a day within three years from the day of the conclusion of such contract for revolving guarantee on loans, and any change which is intended to change the principal determination date to a day preceding the original principal determination date). on Loans)
The principal for the principal obligation under a contract for revolving guarantee on loans shall be determined if: any security interest with respect to a claim the subject- matter of which is payment of money on any property of the relevant principal obligor or guarantor; provided, however, that this provision shall apply only in cases where the proceedings for the compulsory execution or exercise of the security interest have been commenced; ruling of the commencement of bankruptcy procedures; or Obligation in cases where Guarantor is Juridical Person)
In cases of a contract for revolving guarantee under which the guarantor is a juridical person and the scope of the principal obligation thereof includes an obligation on loans, if the maximum amount provided in paragraph 1 of Article 465-2 is not provided, if the principal determination date is not specified, or if the provision on the determination date or any change thereof would not be effective should the provisions of paragraph 1 or paragraph 3 of Article 465-3 be applied, a contract of guarantee with regard to the right to obtain reimbursement of the guarantor for the contract for revolving guarantee against the principal obligor (excluding cases where the guarantor is a juridical person) shall not be effective.

Assignment of Claims
Assignability of Claims
A claim may be assigned; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where its nature does not permit the assignment.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not apply in cases where the parties have manifested their intention to the contrary; provided, however, that such manifestation of intention may not be asserted against a third party without knowledge. Parties)
The assignment of a nominative claim may not be asserted against the applicable obligor or any other third party, unless the assignor gives a notice thereof to the obligor or the obligor has acknowledged the same.
The notice or acknowledgement set forth in the preceding paragraph may not be asserted against a third party other than the obligor unless the notice or acknowledgement is made using an instrument bearing a fixed date.
Defense of Obligor upon Assignment of Nominative Claim
In the cases where the obligor has given the acknowledgement referred to in the preceding Article without objection, even if there are grounds which could have been raised as a defense against the assignor, he/she may not raise such grounds as a defense against the assignee. In such case, if the obligor has paid any money or delivered anything or assumed a new obligation to or for the benefit of the assignor to obtain the extinction of his/her obligation, the obligor may recover the money paid or other thing delivered, or may deem that the new obligation had not been assumed, as the case may be.
In cases where the assignor has merely given notice of the assignment, the obligor may raise any ground as a defense against the assignee which accrues vis-a-vis the assignor before he/she receives such notice as a defense against the assignee. Third Parties)
The assignment of any debt payable to order may not be asserted against the relevant obligor or any other third party unless the certificate representing such claim is tendered to the assignee with the endorsement of the relevant assignment.
Examination Right of Obligor of Debt Payable to Order
The obligor of any debt payable to order shall have the right, but not the obligation, to examine the authenticity of the identity of the bearer of the relevant certificate and the signature and seal affixed thereon; provided, however, that the performance of the applicable obligation shall be void if the obligor has knowledge or is grossly negligent.
Examination Right of Obligor of Claim Payable to Obligee or Holder
The provisions of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases where any certificate regarding the claim specifies the name of the obligee and note that the payment should be made to the bearer of such certificate. Order)
The obligor of a debt payable to order may not use any grounds which could have been raised as defenses against the obligee before the assignment of the relevant debt payable to order as defenses against an assignee without knowledge, except for the matter specified on the relevant certificate or any result which necessarily arises from the nature of such certificate. Certificate of Claims)
The provisions of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to a bearer certificate of claims.

Extinction of Claims
Performance
Performance
Performance by Third Parties
The performance of an obligation may be effected by a third party; provided, however, that, this shall not apply in cases where the nature of such obligation does not permit such performance or the parties have manifested their intention to the contrary.
A third party who has no interest in an obligation may not perform the obligation against the will of the obligor.
Recover of any Property Tendered to Perform Obligation
In cases where a person who performed his/her obligation delivered any property owned by others as the performance of the obligation, the person who made such performance may not recover such property unless he/she effects an effective performance de novo.
In cases where any possessor who has limited capacity to act with respect to the act of assignment delivers any property to perform any obligation, and later rescinds such performance, the relevant possessor may not recover such property unless he/she effects an effective performance de novo. is Consumed or Assigned)
In the case referred to in the preceding two Articles, if an obligee without knowledge consumes or assigns any property which he/she received as the performance of the obligation, such performance shall be effective. In such case, if the relevant obligee has received any request for compensation from a third party, he/she shall not be precluded from seeking reimbursement from the person who performed the obligation.
Performance to a Holder of Quasi-Possession of Claim
Any performance made vis-a-vis a holder of quasi-possession of the claim shall remain effective to the extent the person who performed such obligation acted without knowledge, and was free from any negligence.
Performance to Person Without Authority to Receive Performance
Except as provided in the preceding Article, any performance made vis-a-vis any person who has no authority to receive the performance shall have the effect only to the extent the relevant obligee is enriched as a result thereof.
Performance to Bearer of Receipt
A bearer of a receipt is deemed to have the authority to accept performance; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the person who made the performance knew, or was negligent in not knowing, that the bearer did not have the authority.
Performance by Third-party Obligor who had been Ordered to Suspend Payment
If a third-party obligor who has been enjoined from making payment has paid his/her obligation to his/her own obligee, the relevant attaching obligee shall be entitled to request such third-party obligor to make payment de novo to the extent he/she suffered the damages.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the relevant third-party obligor from exercising his/her right to obtain reimbursement from his/her obligee.
Substitute Performance
If an obligor, in lieu of the performance he/she originally incurred, provided any other type of performance with the acknowledgment of the obligee, such performance shall have the same effect as that of the original performance.
Delivery of Specific Thing in its Existing State
If the subject of a claim is the delivery of a specific thing, the person who intends to effect any performance must deliver such thing on an "as-is" basis as of the time when the delivery is due.
Place of Performance
Unless any other intention is manifested with respect to the place where the performance should take place, the delivery of a specific thing must be effected at the place where such thing was located when the relevant claim accrued, and the discharge of any other obligation must be effected at the current domicile of the obligee, respectively.
Expense of Performance
Unless any other intention is manifested with respect to the expense of performance, such expenses shall be borne by the obligor; provided, however, that, in cases the relevant obligee caused the expense of performance to increase by relocating his/her domicile or taking any other actions, such incremental amount shall be borne by the obligee.
Request for Issuance of Receipt
Any person who made the performance shall be entitled to request the person who received the performance to issue a receipt.
Request for Return of Claim Instrument
In the cases where there is any instrument which evidences the claim, if the person who makes the performance has completed his/her entire performance, he/she may demand the return of such instrument.
Designation of Obligations to be Performed
In the cases where an obligor owes to a single obligee more than one obligations which requires the performance of the same kind, if any performance tendered to discharge the obligation is not sufficient to extinguish all obligations, the person who tenders the performance may, at the time of such tender, designate particular obligations to which such performance should be allocated before any others.
If the person who tenders the performance does not make the designation pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph, the person who receives the performance may, at the time of such receipt, designate a particular obligation to which such performance should be allocated before any others; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the person who tenders the performance immediately raises his/her objection to such allocation.
The designation of the performance under the preceding two paragraphs shall be effected by manifesting the intention to the counterparty.
Statutory Allocation
In cases where neither the person who tenders the performance nor the person who receives such performance does not designate the allocation of performance pursuant to the provision of the preceding Article, the allocation shall be effected as stipulated in each of the following items: due yet, the applicable performance shall be allocated to those which are due; applicable performance shall be allocated in the order of the obligations which shall result in more benefit to the obligor when performed; performed, the applicable performance shall be allocated in the order of the obligations which have, or should have, the earliest due date; and listed in the preceding two items shall be allocated in proportion to the amount of each obligation.
Allocation in cases More than One Performance Should be Tendered
In the cases where more than one performance should be tendered to discharge a single obligation, if the person who must perform tenders any performance which is not sufficient to extinguish such obligation in its entirety, the provision of the preceding two Articles shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Allocation in cases Principal, Interest, and Expenses Should be Paid
In cases where the obligor should pay the principal as well as the applicable interest and expenses with respect to one or more obligation(s), if the person who must perform tenders any performance which is not sufficient to extinguish such obligation in its entirety, such performance must be allocated first to the expense, and then to the interest and principal, in this order.
The provision of Article 489 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph.
Effect of Tender of Performances
Upon tendering the performance, the relevant obligor shall be relieved from any and all responsibilities which may arise from the nonperformance of the obligation.
Method of Tender of Performances
The tender of the performance must be made actually consistent with the main purport of the obligation; provided, however, that, if the obligee refuses to accept such performance in advance, or any act is required on the part of the obligee with respect to the performance of the obligation, it shall be sufficient if the obligor demands the acceptance thereof by giving a notice that the tender of the performance has been prepared.
Performance
Deposit
If an obligee refuses, or is unable, to accept the performance, the person who can make the performance (hereinafter in this Division referred to as the "performer") may be relieved from his/her obligation by depositing the subject-matter of the performance with an official depository. The same shall apply in cases the performer is unable to ascertain the obligee without any negligence on the part of the performer.
Method of Deposit
The deposit pursuant to the provision of the preceding Article must be made with the official depository having jurisdiction over the district where the relevant obligation must be performed.
In cases where there is no specific provision in the laws and regulations with respect to the official depository, the court must, at the request of the performer, designate the depository and appoint a custodian of the property to be deposited.
A person who has effected a deposit pursuant to the provision of the preceding Article must notify the obligee of the deposit without delay.
Recovery of Deposited Property
As long as the obligee does not accept the deposit, or the judgment which pronounces that the deposit is effective does not become unappealable, the performer may recover the deposited property. In such case, it is deemed that no deposit has been effected.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply in cases any pledge or mortgage has been extinguished due to the deposit.
Property Not Suitable for Deposit
If any subject of the performance is not suitable for deposit, or such property is likely to suffer any loss or damage, the performer may, with the permission of the court, sell such property at public auction and deposit the proceeds of such sales with the official depository. The same shall apply in cases excessive expenses are required for the preservation of such property.
Requirements for Acceptance of Deposited Property
In cases where the obligor is required to perform in exchange for the performance of the obligee, the obligee may not accept the relevant deposited property unless he/she tenders his/her performance.
Performance
Voluntary Subrogation
A person who has performed the obligation for the benefit of an obligor may be subrogated to the claim of the obligee by acquiring the acknowledgment of the obligee upon such performance.
The provision of Article 467 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case set forth in the preceding paragraph.
Statutory Subrogation
A person who has legitimate interest in effecting performance shall be subrogated by operation of law to the claim of the obligee by effecting performance.
Effect of Subrogation by Performance
A person who is subrogated to the claim of the obligee pursuant to the provisions of the preceding two articles may exercise any and all rights possessed by such obligee as the effect of, and as a security for, such right to the extent he/she may seek reimbursement under his/her own right; provided, however, that: applicable statutory lien, pledge of real estate, or mortgage, a guarantor may not be subrogated to the claim of the obligee vis-a-vis any third party acquirer of the real estate which is encumbered by such statutory lien, pledge of real estate, or mortgage; obligee vis-a-vis the guarantor; subrogated to the claim of the obligee vis-a-vis other third party acquirers in proportion to the value of each real estate; obligee vis-a-vis other third party pledgors in proportion to the value of each property; claim of the obligee shall be effected depending on the number of such persons involved; provided, however, that, if there are more than one third party pledgor, such persons shall be subrogated to the claim of the obligee in proportion to the value of each property with respect only to the residual amount which remains after deduction of the portion to be borne by the guarantor; and question is real estate, the provisions of item 1 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Subrogation by Partial Performance
If any performance by subrogation occurs with respect to any portion of a claim, the subrogee shall exercise his/her right together with the obligee in proportion to the value of his/her performance.
In the case set forth in the preceding paragraph, the cancellation of a contract based on the failure to perform the obligation may be effected only by the obligee. In such case, the obligee must reimburse to the subrogee the value of the performance he/she effected plus interest.
Delivery of Claim Instrument by Obligee
An obligee who has received full performance by way of performance by subrogation must deliver to the subrogee the instruments regarding the claim and any security he/she possesses.
In cases where any performance by subrogation occurs with respect to any portion of a claim, the obligee must enter such subrogation in the instruments regarding the claim and allow the subrogee to supervise the preservation of the security he/she possesses.
Loss of Security by Obligee
In cases where there exists a person who has the right of subrogation pursuant to the provision of Article 500, if the obligee lost, or diminished, his/her security due to his/her intentional act or negligence, the person who has the right of subrogation shall be relieved to the extent he/she can no longer seek the reimbursement due to such loss or diminution.
Set-offs
Requirements for Set-offs
In cases where two persons mutually owe to the other any obligation with the same kind of purpose, if both obligations are due, each obligor may be relieved from his/her own obligation by setting off each value thereof against the corresponding amount of the obligation of the other obligor; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where the nature of the obligation does not permit such set-off.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not apply in cases where the relevant party manifests his/her intention to the contrary; provided, however, that such manifestation of intention may not be asserted against a third party without knowledge.
Method and Effect of Set-offs
Set-offs shall be effected by means of manifestation of one party's intention to the other. In such case, no condition or time limit may be added to such manifestation of intention.
The manifestation of intention set forth in the preceding paragraph shall take effect retroactively as of the time when the obligations of both parties became due and suitable for set-off.
Set-offs between Obligations with Different Places of Performance
Set-offs may be effected even if the place of performance of both obligations are different. In such case, the party who intends to effect the set-off shall be liable for any damages suffered by the counterparty as result of such set-off.
Set-offs Intended to Invoke a Claim Extinguished by Prescription 
In cases where any claim which was extinguished by a prescription had been suitable for set-off prior to such extinguishment, the relevant obligee may effect the set-off. Acts)
If any claim arises from a tortious act, the relevant obligor may not assert the set-off against the obligee.
Prohibition of Set-offs Against Any Claim Immune from Attachment
If any claim is immune from any attachment, the relevant obligor may not assert the set-off against the obligee.
Prohibition of Set-offs Against Any Claim Subject to Injunction
A third-party obligor who has been enjoined from making payment may not assert the set-off against any after-acquired claim against the relevant attaching obligee.
Allocation of Set-off
The provisions of Articles 488 to 491 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the set-off.
Novation
Novation
If the parties conclude a contract which changes any element of an obligation, such obligation shall be extinguished by novation.
It is deemed that an element of obligation has been changed if a conditional obligation is made an unconditional obligation, if a condition is added to an unconditional obligation, or if any condition on an obligation is changed.
Novation by Substitution of Obligor
A novation by substitution of obligor may be effected between the obligee and a person who becomes the obligor after the novation; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where it is contrary to the intention of the obligor prior to the novation.
Novation by Substitution of Obligee
A novation by substitution of obligee may not be asserted against a third party unless it is made using an instrument bearing a fixed date.
The provisions of paragraph 1 of Article 468 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the novation by substitution of obligee.
Cases where Obligations Existing Prior to Novation are not Extinguished
If any obligation which arises by novation is not established or is rescinded on the ground of illegality or due to reasons unknown to the parties, the obligation which existed prior to the novation shall not be extinguished.
Conversion of Security to Obligation After Novation
To the extent of the purpose of the obligation in effect prior to the novation, the parties to the novation may convert the pledge or mortgage created as the security of such obligation to the obligation in effect after the novation; provided, however, that, in cases where any third party created such security, the acknowledgment of such third party must be obtained.
Release
If an obligee manifests his/her intention to release an obligation to the obligor, such obligation shall be extinguished.
Merger
If a claim and obligation becomes vested in the same person, such claim shall be extinguished; provided, however, that, this shall not apply to the cases where such claim is the subject-matter of the right of a third party.


Contracts
General Provisions
Formation of Contracts
Offers that Specify Period for Acceptance
An offer which specifies a period for acceptance may not be revoked.
If an offeror does not receive notice of acceptance of the offer set forth in the preceding paragraph within the period referred to in the same paragraph, the offer shall cease to be effective.
Late Arrival of Notices of Acceptance
Even in cases where the notice of acceptance of the offer under Paragraph 1 of the preceding Article arrives after the lapse of the period referred to in the same paragraph, if the offeror is in a position to know that the notice was dispatched at a time which, under normal circumstances, would have allowed the notice to arrive within that period, the offeror must dispatch a notice of late arrival to the other party without delay; provided, however, that this shall not apply when the offeror dispatches the notice of delay before the arrival of the notice of acceptance.
When the offeror fails to give the notice of late arrival referred to in the main clause of the preceding paragraph, the notice of acceptance shall be deemed to have arrived within the period referred to in Paragraph 1 of the preceding Article.
Effect of Delayed Acceptance
The offeror may deem a delayed acceptance to be a new offer.
Offers that do not Specify Period for Acceptance
An offer made to a person at a distance without specifying a period for acceptance may not be revoked until the lapse of a reasonable period for the offeror to receive a notice of acceptance.
Offeror's Death or Loss of Capacity to Act
The provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 97 shall not apply where the offeror expresses his/her intention to the contrary, or the other party has come to know the fact of the offeror's death or loss of capacity to act.
Time of Formation of Contract between Persons at Distance
A contract between persons at a distance shall be formed upon dispatch of the notice of acceptance.
In cases where no notice of acceptance is required due to the offeror's manifestation of intention or usage of trade, the contract shall be formed upon the occurrence of any fact which ought to be regarded as a manifestation of intention of acceptance.
Late Arrival of Notices of Revocation of Offer
Even if a notice to revoke an offer arrives after the dispatch of the acceptance notice, if the offeree is in a position to know that the notice was dispatched at a time which, under normal circumstances would have allowed the notice to arrive before the dispatch of the acceptance notice, the offeree must dispatch a notice of the late arrival to the offeror without delay.
If the offeree fails to give the notice of late arrival referred to in the preceding paragraph, it shall be deemed that no contract was formed.
Acceptances which Modify Offer
If the offeree has accepted the offer by adding any condition or by making any other modification, it shall be deemed that the offeree has refused the offer and has made a new offer.
Advertisements Offering Prizes
A person who places an advertisement to the effect that any person who performs a defined act will be given a set reward (hereinafter in this Subsection referred to as an "advertiser offering prizes") shall be obligated to give the reward to the person who has performed the act.
Revocation of Advertisements Offering Prizes
In the case set forth in the preceding Article, the advertiser offering prizes may revoke its advertisement using a method identical to that used for the above advertisement whilst no person has completed the designated act; provided, however, that this shall not apply when a statement to the effect that the offer will not be revoked was made in the advertisement.
Where revocation may not be carried out by the method provided in the main clause of the preceding paragraph, the revocation may be carried out by another method. In such cases, the revocation shall only be effective against persons with knowledge of the revocation.
If the advertiser offering prizes specifies the period during which the designated act must be performed, it shall be presumed that the advertiser has waived its right to revoke.
Right to Receive Rewards in Advertisements Offering Prizes
If more than one person has performed the act designated in the advertisement, only the person who performed the act first shall be entitled to receive the reward.
Where two or more persons have performed the act set forth in the preceding paragraph simultaneously, each shall be entitled to receive an equal share of the reward; provided, however, that the person entitled to the reward shall be selected by lot if the reward is by nature indivisible, or the advertisement provides that only one person is entitled to receive the reward.
The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall not apply if the advertisement expresses any intention to the contrary.
Advertisement Offering Prizes to Most Outstanding Applicant
If, in cases where two or more persons have performed the act designated in the advertisement, the reward is to be given only to the most outstanding applicant, the advertisement shall be effective only if it specifies the application period.
In the cases of the preceding paragraph, the most outstanding applicant shall be judged by the person specified in the advertisement and if no such person is specified in the advertisement, by the person who places the advertisement.
Applicants may not raise any objection to the judge's decision referred to in the preceding paragraph.
The provision of the second paragraph of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where the acts of two or more persons are judged to be equal.
Effect of Contracts
Defense for Simultaneous Performance
A party to a bilateral contract may refuse to perform his/her own obligation until the other party tenders the performance of his/her obligation; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the obligation of the other party is not yet due.
Obligees to Assume Risk
In cases where the purpose of a bilateral contract is the creation or transfer of real rights regarding specified things, if the things have been lost or damaged due to reasons not attributable to the obligor, such loss or damage shall fall on the obligee.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply to any contract regarding unspecified things from the time when the things have been identified in accordance with the provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 401.
Assumption of Risk in Bilateral Contract with Condition Precedent
The provisions of the preceding Article shall not apply where the subject matter of a bilateral contract with conditions precedent is lost whilst the conditions are pending.
If the subject matter of a bilateral contract with conditions precedent has been lost or damaged due to reasons not attributable to the obligor, the loss or damage shall fall on obligee.
In cases where the subject matter of a bilateral contract with conditions precedent has been lost or damaged due to reasons attributable to the obligor, if the condition has been satisfied, the obligee may, at his/her choice, demand performance or exercise the obligee's right to cancel. In such cases, claims for damages shall not be precluded.
Obligors' Assumption of Risk
Except in the cases provided for in the preceding two Articles, if the performance of any obligation has become impossible due to reasons not attributable to either party, the obligor shall not have the right to receive performance in return.
If the performance of any obligation has become impossible due to reasons attributable to the obligee, the obligor shall not lose his/her right to receive performance in return. In such cases, if the obligor gains any benefit as a result of being released from his/her own obligation, the obligor must reimburse the obligee for the benefit.
Contracts for the Benefit of Third Parties
If one of the parties promises in a contract that he/she will tender a certain performance to any third party, the third party shall have the right to claim that performance directly from the obligor.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, rights of the third party shall accrue when the third party has expressed his/her intention to the obligor to enjoy the benefit of the contract under that paragraph.
Determination of Rights of the Third Party
After rights of the third party have come into existence in accordance with the provisions of the preceding Article, the parties may not modify or extinguish those rights.
Obligors' Defense
The obligor may raise the defense founded on the contract referred to in Paragraph 1 of Article 537 against a third party who is to enjoy the benefit of the contract.
Cancellation of Contracts
Exercise of Right to Cancel
If one of the parties has a right to cancel in accordance with the provisions of the contract or law, the cancellation shall be effected by manifestation of intention to the other party.
The manifestation of intention under the preceding paragraph may not be revoked.
Right to Cancel for Delayed Performance
In cases where one of the parties does not perform his/her obligations, if the other party demands performance of the obligations, specifying a reasonable period and no performance is tendered during that period, the other party may cancel the contract.
Right to Cancel for Delayed Performance where Time is of the Essence
In cases where, due to the nature of the contract or a manifestation of intention by the parties, the purpose of the contract cannot be achieved unless the performance is carried out at a specific time and date or within a certain period of time, if one of the parties has failed to perform at the time that period lapses, the other party may immediately cancel the contract without making the demand referred to in the preceding Article.
Right to Cancel for Impossibility of Performance
If performance has become impossible, in whole or in part, the obligee may cancel the contract; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the failure to perform the obligation is due to reasons not attributable to the obligor.
Indivisible Nature of Right to Cancel
If one party is constituted of two or more persons, the cancellation of the contract may be effected only by, or against, all of those persons.
In the case set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the right to cancel is extinguished with respect to one of the persons who constitute a party, it shall also be extinguished with respect to the other persons.
Effect of Cancellation
If one of the parties exercises his/her right to cancel, each party shall assume an obligation to restore the other party to that other party's original position; provided, however, that this shall not prejudice the rights of a third party.
In the case set forth in the main clause of the preceding paragraph, if any monies are to be refunded, interest must accrue from the time of the receipt of those monies.
The exercise of the right to cancel shall not preclude claims for damages.
Cancellation of Contract and Simultaneous Performance
The provisions of Article 533 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the preceding Article.
Extinguishment of Right to Cancel by Demand
If no period is provided for the exercise of the right to cancel, the other party may issue a notice of demand to the holder of the right to cancel, specifying a reasonable period, to the effect that the holder of the right to cancel is to give a definite answer as to whether or not the right will be exercised within that period. In such cases, if no notice of cancellation is received within that period, the right to cancel shall be extinguished.
Extinguishment of Right to Cancel by Acts of Holder of Right to Cancel
The right to cancel shall be extinguished if the holder of the right to cancel has significantly damaged, or has become unable to return, the subject matter of the contract due to his/her act or negligence, or has converted the subject matter into any other kind of thing by processing or alteration.
The right to cancel shall not be extinguished if the subject matter of the contract has been lost or damaged due to reasons not attributable to any act or negligence of the holder of the right to cancel.

Gifts
Gifts
Gifts shall become effective by the manifestation by one of the parties of his/her intention to give his/her property to the other party gratuitously, and the acceptance of the other party thereof.
Revocation of Gift Not in Writing
Gifts not in writing may be revoked by either party; provided, however, that this shall not apply to any portion of the gift for which performance has been completed.
Warranty by Donor
The donor shall not be liable for any defect in or absence of the thing or right that is the subject matter of the gift; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the donor has knowledge of the defect or absence and fails to inform the donee thereof.
With respect to encumbered gifts, the donor shall assume a warranty identical to that borne by the seller, to the extent of that encumbrance.
Periodic Gifts
Periodic gifts shall lose its effect on the death of the donor or the donee.
Encumbered Gifts
With respect to gifts with burden, in addition to the provisions of this Section, the provisions regarding bilateral contracts shall apply mutatis mutandis, to the extent those provisions are not inconsistent with the nature of gifts with burden.
Gifts on Donor's Death
With respect to gifts that become effective on the death of the donor, the provisions regarding testamentary gifts shall apply mutatis mutandis, to the extent they are not inconsistent with the nature of gifts that become effective on the death of the donor.

Sale
General Provisions
Sale
A sale shall become effective when one of the parties promises to transfer a certain real rights to the other party and the other party promises to pay the purchase money for it.
Pre-contract of Sales Exercisable by One Party
A pre-contract to sell or purchase made by one party shall take the effect of a sale when the other party has manifested his/her intention to complete such sale.
If no period is provided in relation to the manifestation of intention set forth in the preceding paragraph, the other party to the pre-contact may issue a notice of demand to the other party, specifying a reasonable period, to the effect that the other party is to give a definite answer as to whether or not he/she will complete the sale within that period. In such cases, if the other party fails to give a definite answer within that period, the pre-contract of sale by one party shall lose its effect.
Earnest Money
When the buyer delivers earnest money to the seller, the buyer may cancel the contract by forfeiting his/her earnest money or the seller may cancel the contract by reimbursing twice its amount, until either party commences performance of the contract.
The provisions of Paragraph 3 of Article 545 shall not apply to cases set forth in the preceding paragraph.
Expenses of Contracts for Sale
The expenses of contracts for sale shall be borne equally by both parties.
Mutatis Mutandis Application to Contracts for Value
The provisions of this Section shall apply mutatis mutandis to contracts for value other than contracts for sale; provided, however that this shall not apply when it is not permitted by the nature of the contract for value.
Effect of Sale
Seller's Obligation when Selling Rights of Others
If the subject matter of the sale is the rights of others, the seller shall assume an obligation to acquire the rights and transfer the same to the buyer.
Seller's Warranty when Selling Rights of Others
In the cases set forth in the preceding Article, if the seller cannot acquire and transfer to the buyer the rights the seller has sold, the buyer may cancel the contract. In such cases, if the buyer knew, at the time of the contract, that the rights did not belong to the seller, the buyer may not demand compensation for damages.
Innocent Seller's Right of Cancellation in a Sale of Others' Rights
In cases where the seller, at the moment of the contract, does not know that the rights the seller has sold do not belong to him/her, if the seller cannot acquire the rights and transfer the same to the buyer, the seller may cancel the contract by compensating any damages.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the buyer, at the moment of the contract, knows that the rights the buyer has bought do not belong to the seller, the seller may cancel the contract by simply notifying the buyer to the effect that the seller cannot transfer the rights sold.
Seller's Warranty where Rights Partially Belonged to Others
If the seller cannot transfer any part of the rights which are the subject matter of the sale because the part of the rights belongs to others, the seller may demand a reduction of the purchase money in proportion to the value of the part in shortage.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, a buyer in good faith may cancel the contract if the buyer would not have bought the rights if the rights consisted only of the remaining portion.
A demand for the reduction in the purchase money or cancellation of the contract shall not preclude a buyer in good faith from making a claim for damages.
The rights under the preceding Article must be exercised within one year from the time when the buyer knew the facts if the buyer was in good faith, or within one year from the time of the contract if the buyer had knowledge, as the case may be. Object)
The provisions of the preceding two Articles shall apply mutatis mutandis in cases where there is any shortage in the object of a sale made for a designated quantity, or in cases where part of the object was already lost at the time of the contract, if the buyer did not know of the shortage or loss.
Seller's Warranty in cases of Superficies or Other Rights
In cases where the subject matter of the sale is encumbered with for the purpose of a superficies, an emphyteusis, an easement, a right of retention or a pledge, if the buyer does not know the same and cannot achieve the purpose of the contract on account thereof, the buyer may cancel the contract. In such cases, if the contract cannot be cancelled, the buyer may only demand compensation for damages.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis in cases where an easement that was referred to as being in existence for the benefit of immovable property that is the subject matter of a sale, does not exist, and in cases where a leasehold is registered with respect to the immovable property.
In the cases set forth in the preceding two paragraphs, the cancellation of the contract or claim for damages must be made within one year from the time when the buyer comes to know the facts.
Seller's Warranty in cases of Mortgage or Other Rights
If the buyer loses his/her ownership of immovable property that is the object of a sale because of the exercise of an existing statutory lien or mortgage, the buyer may cancel the contract.
If the buyer preserves his/her ownership by incurring expenditure for costs, he/she may claim reimbursement of those costs from the seller.
In the cases set forth in the preceding two paragraphs, the buyer may claim compensation if he/she suffered loss.
Warranty in cases of Compulsory Auctions
The successful bidder at compulsory auction may cancel the contract or demand a reduction from the purchase money against the obligor in accordance with the provisions from Article 561 through to the preceding Article.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the obligor is insolvent, the successful bidder may demand total or partial reimbursement of the proceeds against the obligees who received the distribution of the proceeds.
In the cases set forth in the preceding two paragraphs, if obligors knew of the absence of the object or right and did not disclose the same, or if obligors knew of the absence but demanded an auction, the successful bidder may demand compensation for damages against those persons.
Seller's Warranty for Claims
If the seller of a claim warrants the solvency of the obligor, it shall be presumed that the seller warranted the solvency as at the time of the contract.
If the seller of a claim which is not due yet warrants the future solvency of the obligor, it shall be presumed that he/she warranted the solvency as at the due date.
Seller's Warranty against Defects
If there is any latent defect in the subject matter of a sale, the provisions of Article 566 shall apply mutatis mutandis; provided, however, that this shall not apply in cases of compulsory auction.
Seller's Warranty and Simultaneous Performance
The provisions of Article 533 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases set forth from Article 563 through to Article 566 and in the preceding Article.
Special Agreement Disclaiming Warranty
Even if the seller makes a special agreement to the effect that the seller will not provide the warranties set forth from Article 560 through to the preceding Article, the seller may not be released from that responsibility with respect to any fact that the seller knew but did not disclose, and with respect to any right that the seller himself/herself created for or assigned to a third party.
Due Date for Payment of Purchase money
If there is a due date for the delivery of the subject matter of the sale, it shall be presumed that the same due date was also agreed for the payment of the purchase money.
Place of Payment of Purchase money
If the purchase money is to be paid simultaneously with delivery of the subject matter of the sale, the payment must be made at the place of delivery.
Ownership in Fruit and Payment of Interest on Purchase money
If any subject matter of a sale that is not delivered yet bears any fruit, the fruit shall vest in the seller.
The buyer shall assume an obligation to pay the interest on the purchase money from the day of delivery; provided, however, that, if a due date is provided for the payment of the purchase money, it shall not be necessary to pay the interest until that due date arrives.
Refusal by Buyer to Pay Purchase money where Loss of Rights is Likely
If the buyer is likely to lose the rights he/she has bought, in whole or in part, due to the existence of persons who assert rights to the subject matter of the sale, the buyer may refuse to pay the purchase money, in whole or in part, in proportion to the extent of that likelihood; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the seller has provided reasonable security.
Refusal by Buyer to Pay Purchase money in cases of Registered Mortgage
If any mortgage is registered on immovable property that has been purchased, the buyer may refuse to pay the purchase money until the completion of the procedures of the claim for extinguishment of the mortgage. In such cases, the seller may demand that the buyer file the claim for extinguishment of the mortgage without delay.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where a statutory lien or pledge is registered on the immovable property that has been bought.
Seller's Demand for Deposit of Purchase money
In the cases of the preceding two paragraphs, the seller may demand that the buyer deposit the purchase money.
Redemption
Special Agreement on Redemption
The buyer of immovable property may cancel the sale by refunding the purchase money and costs of the contract paid by the buyer in accordance with a special agreement on redemption executed simultaneously with the contract for sale. In such cases, unless a contrary intention is manifested by the parties, it shall be deemed that the fruit of the immovable property and the interest on the purchase money have been set off against each other.
Period for Redemption
The period for the redemption may not exceed ten years. If any special agreement provides for any period longer than the above, the period shall be ten years.
If a period for the redemption is agreed, no further extension may be effected subsequently.
If no period for the redemption is agreed, the redemption must be effected within five years.
Perfection of Special Agreement on Redemption
If the special agreement on redemption is registered simultaneously with the contract for sale, the redemption shall also be effective against third parties.
The rights of a lessee who effected registration can be asserted against the seller while the lease remains effective, limited to a period not exceeding one year; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the lease is entered into with the purpose of harming the seller.
Exercise of Right of Redemption by way of Subrogation
If an obligee of the seller intends to effect redemption on behalf of the seller in accordance with the provisions of Article 423, the buyer may extinguish the right of redemption by paying the debts of the seller, to the extent of the balance obtained by deducting the amount the seller is to pay from the current value of the immovable property as evaluated by a court-appointed appraiser, and, if any positive balance remains, by refunding the same to the seller.
Implementation of Redemption
A seller may not effect redemption unless the seller provides the purchase money and the costs of the contract within the period provided for in Article 580.
If a buyer or subsequent acquirer incurs expenses with respect to immovable property, the seller must reimburse those expenses in accordance with the provisions of Article 196; provided, however, that, with respect to useful expenses, the court may, at the seller's request, grant a reasonable period for the reimbursement.
Sale of Co-ownership Interest with Special Agreements on Redemption
If one of the co-owners of immovable property sells his/her equity interest with special agreements on its redemption and the immovable property is then divided or subjected to auction, the seller may redeem the portion or purchase money that the buyer receives or is to receive; provided, however, that any division or auction effected without notice to the seller may not be asserted against the seller.
In the cases of the preceding Article, if the buyer is the successful bidder at the auction of the immovable property, the seller may effect the redemption by paying the auction price and the costs provided for in Article 583. In such cases, the seller shall acquire full ownership of the immovable property.
If the buyer has become the successful bidder at an auction as the result of the request of division by other joint owner(s), the seller may not effect the redemption with respect only to his/her own share.

Exchange
An exchange shall become effective by the mutual promises by the parties to transfer any property right other than the ownership of money.
In cases where one of the parties promises to transfer the ownership of money together with other rights, the provisions regarding purchase money for sale contracts shall apply mutatis mutandis to that money.

Loans for Consumption
Loans for Consumption
A loan for consumption shall become effective when one of the parties receives money or other things from the other party by promising that he/she will return by means of things that are the same in kind, quality and quantity.
Quasi-loans for Consumption
In cases where any person has an obligation to provide money or other things under any arrangement which is not a loan for consumption, if the parties agree to regard such things as the subject matter of a loan for consumption, it shall be deemed that this establishes a loan for consumption. Procedures)
The pre-contract of a loan for consumption shall lose its effect if a ruling for the commencement of bankruptcy procedures is subsequently made against one of the parties.
Lender's Warranty
If there is any latent defect in any borrowed Thing in a loan for consumption with interest, the lender must replace it with another Thing without defect. In such cases, claims for damages shall not be precluded.
In a loan for consumption without interest, the borrower may return the value of a borrowed Thing that is defective. In such cases, the provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis if the lender knew of the defect but did not disclose the same to the borrower.
Timing of Returns
If the parties do not define the time for return of borrowed Things, the lender may demand their return, specifying a reasonable period.
The borrower may return borrowed Things at any time.
Reimbursement of Value
If the borrower has become unable to return Things in the same kind, quality and quantity as that of the Things the borrower received from the lender, the borrower must return the current value of the Things; provided, however, that this shall not apply in the cases provided for in Paragraph 2 of Article 402.

Loans for Use
Loans for Use
A loan for use shall become effective when one of the parties receives a defined Thing from the other party by promising that he/she will return the Thing after he/she has gratuitously made use of and taken the profits of the same .
Borrower's Use and Profit
A borrower must make use of and take the profits of the Thing in compliance with the method of use specified by the contract or by the nature of the Thing which is the subject matter of the contract.
A borrower may not allow third parties to make use of or take the profits of the Thing without obtaining the approval of the lender.
If a borrower has made use of or taken the profits of the Thing in violation of the preceding two paragraphs, the lender may cancel the contract.
Responsibility for Costs of Borrowed Things
The borrower shall bear the ordinarily necessary costs of borrowed Things.
The provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 583 shall apply mutatis mutandis to costs other than the ordinarily necessary costs under the preceding paragraph.
Lender's Warranty
The provisions of Article 551 shall apply mutatis mutandis to loans for use.
Timing of Returns of Borrowed Things
A borrower must return borrowed Things at the time specified in the contract.
When the parties have not specified a time for return, the borrower must return the borrowed Things when he/she has completed to make use of or take the profits of the same in compliance with the purposes provided for in the contract; provided, however, that the lender may demand the immediate return of the borrowed Things even before the completion of using or taking profits if a period sufficient for using or taking profits has elapsed.
If the parties have not specified the timing of the return and the purposes of the using and taking profits, the lender may demand the return of the borrowed Things at any time.
Removal by Borrower
A borrower may restore a borrowed Thing to its original condition and remove anything attached to the same.
Termination of Loan for Use upon Death of Borrower
Loans for use shall lose its effect on the death of the borrower. Reimbursement of Costs)
Claims for compensation for damages resulting from using or taking profits of the Thing inconsistent with the main purport of the contract, and for the reimbursement of costs incurred by the borrower, must be submitted within one year from the time when the lender receives the return of the borrowed Things.

Leases
General Provisions
Leases
A lease shall become effective when one of the parties promises to make a certain Thing available for the using and taking the profits by the other party and the other party promises to pay rent for the same.
Short-term Leases
In cases where a person with limited capacity to act or a person with no authority with respect to the act of disposition makes a lease contract, the leases listed in the following items shall not exceed the terms prescribed respectively in those items: years;
Renewal of Short-term Leases
The terms prescribed in the preceding Article may be renewed; provided, however, that the renewal must be carried out within one year prior to the expiration of the term for land, and within 3 months prior to the expiration of the term for a building, and within 1 month prior to the expiration of the term for a movable.
Duration of Lease
The duration of a lease may not exceed twenty years. Even if the contract prescribes a longer term, the term shall be 20 years.
The duration of a lease may be renewed; provided, however, that such period may not exceed twenty years from the time of the renewal.
Effect of Lease
Perfection of Leasehold
A lease of immovable property, when registered, shall also be effective against a person who subsequently acquires real rights with respect to the immovable property.
Repairs of Leased Things
A lessor shall assume an obligation to effect repairs necessary for using and taking the profits of the leased Things.
The lessee may not refuse if the lessor intends to engage in any act that is necessary for the preservation of the leased Thing.
Act to Preserve against the Will of the Lessee
In cases where the lessor intends to engage in an act to preserve the leased Thing against the will of the lessee, if the lessee cannot achieve the purpose of the lease as a result of the same, the lessee may cancel the contract.
Lessee's Demand for Reimbursement of Costs
If a lessee has defrayed necessary expenses with respect to the leased Thing which ought to be borne by the lessor, the lessee may immediately demand the reimbursement of the same from the lessor.
If the lessee has incurred useful expenses with respect to the leased Thing, the lessor must reimburse those expenses on termination of the lease in compliance with the provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 196; provided, however, that the court may, at the lessor's request, grant a reasonable period for the reimbursement of the same.
Demand for Reduction of Rent due to Decrease in Profits
A lessee of land for the purpose of profit making may, if he/she obtains profits less than the rent due to force majeure, demand that the amount of the rent be reduced to the level of the amount of the profits; provided, however, that this shall not apply with respect to leases of residential land.
Termination due to Decrease in Profits
In the cases of the preceding Article, the lessee referred to in that Article may cancel the contract if he/she has made profits less than the rent for at least two consecutive years due to force majeure.
Demands for Reduction of Rent due to Partial Loss of Leased Thing
If any part of a leased thing is lost due to reasons not attributable to the negligence of the lessee, the lessee may demand a reduction of the rent in proportion to the value of the lost part.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, if the lessee cannot achieve the purpose of the lease with the remaining portion only, the lessee may cancel the contract.
Restrictions on Assignment and Subleasing of Leasehold
A lessee may not assign the lessee's rights or sublease a leased Thing without obtaining the approval of the lessor.
If the lessee allows any third party to make use of or take the profits of a leased Thing in violation of the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the lessor may cancel the contract.
Effect of Subleases
If a lessee lawfully subleases a leased Thing, the sublessee shall assume a direct obligation to the lessor. In such cases, advance payment of rent may not be asserted against the lessor.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the lessor from exercising his/her rights against the lessee.
Timing of Payment of Rent
Rent must be paid at the end of the month with respect to movables, buildings and land for residential purpose, and at the end of the year with respect to other land; provided, however, that, with respect to anything with a harvest season, the rent must be paid without delay after that season.
Obligation of Lessee to Give Notice
If the leased Thing requires any repair, or if any person asserts rights with respect to the leased Thing, the lessee must notify the lessor without delay; provided, however, that this shall not apply if this is already known to the lessor.
Mutatis Mutandis Application of Loans for Use
The provisions of Paragraph 1 of Article 594, Paragraph 1 of Article 597 and Article 598 shall apply mutatis mutandis to leases.
Termination of Leases
Offers to Terminate Leases with Indefinite Terms
If the parties do not specify the term of a lease, either party may request to terminate it at any time. In such cases, the leases listed in the following items shall terminate on the expiration of the respective periods from the day of the request to terminate prescribed respectively in those items:
With respect to leases of land with harvest seasons, the request to terminate must be made after the end of that season and before the next start of cultivation.
Reservation of Rights to Terminate Leases with Definite Terms
Even if the parties specify the term of a lease, the provisions of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis if one party reserves, or both parties reserve, the right to terminate during that period.
Presumption of Renewal of Leases
In cases where a lessee continues to make use or take the profits of the Thing after the expiration of the term of the lease, if a lessor who knows of the same raises no objection, it shall be presumed that a further lease is entered into under conditions identical to those of the previous lease. In such cases, each party may request to terminate in accordance with the provisions of Article 617.
If one of the parties has provided security for the previous lease, the security shall be extinguished upon expiration of the term; provided, however, that this shall not apply to a security deposit.
Effect of Cancellations of Leases
In cases where a lease is cancelled, the cancellation shall be effective solely toward the future. In such cases, if one of the parties is negligent, claims for damages against that party shall not be precluded. Reimbursement of Costs)
The provisions of Article 600 shall apply mutatis mutandis to leases.

Employment
Employment
An employment contract shall become effective when one of the parties promises to the other party that he/she will engage in work and the other party promises to pay remuneration for the same.
Timing of Payment of Remuneration
An employee may not demand remuneration until the work he/she promised to perform has been completed.
Remuneration specified with reference to a period may be claimed on the expiration of that period.
Restrictions on Assignment of Employer's Rights
An employer may not assign his/her rights to third parties unless the employer obtains the employee's consent.
An employee may not cause any third party to work on his/her behalf unless the employee obtains the employer's consent.
If an employee causes any third party to work in violation of the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the employer may cancel the contract.
Cancellation of Employment with Indefinite Term
If the term of employment exceeds five years, or employment is to continue during the life of either party or any third party, either party may cancel the contract at any time after the expiration of five years; provided, however, that said five years shall be ten years with respect to employment for the purpose of apprenticeship in commerce and industry.
If a person intends to cancel a contract under the provisions of the preceding paragraph, he/she must give notice three months in advance.
Offer to Terminate Employment with Indefinite Term
If the parties have not specified the term of employment, either party may request to terminate at any time. In such cases, employment shall terminate on the expiration of two weeks from the day of the request to terminate.
If remuneration is specified with reference to a period, the request to terminate may be made with respect to the following period of time onward; provided, however, that the request to terminate must be made in the first half of the current period.
If remuneration is specified with reference to a period of six months or more, the request to terminate under the preceding paragraph must be made three months before the termination.
Cancellation of Employment due to Unavoidable Reasons
Even in cases where the parties have specified the term of employment, if there are unavoidable reasons, either party may immediately cancel the contract. In such cases, if the reasons arise from the negligence of either one of the parties, that party shall be liable to the other party for damages.
Presumption of Renewal of Employment
In cases where an employee continues to engage in his/her work after the expiration of a term of employment, if an employer knows of the same and raises no objection, it shall be presumed that the further employment is entered into under conditions identical to those of the previous employment. In such cases, each party may request to termination under the provisions of Article 627.
If either party has provided security for the previous employment, the security shall be extinguished on the expiration of the term; provided, however, that this shall not apply to fidelity bonds.
Effect of Cancellation of Employment
The provisions of Article 620 shall apply mutatis mutandis to employment. Employer)
In cases where the employer is subject to a ruling for the commencement of bankruptcy procedures, the employee or the trustee in bankruptcy may request to terminate under the provisions of Article 627 even if the employment is for a definite term. In such cases, neither party may claim compensation from the other party for damages suffered as a result of the termination.

Contracts for Work
Contracts for Work
A contract for work shall become effective when one of the parties promises to complete work and the other party promises to pay remuneration for the outcome of the work.
Timing of Payment of Remuneration
Remuneration must be paid simultaneously with delivery of the subject matter of work performed; provided, however, that, if no delivery of a Thing is required, the provisions of Article 624(1) shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Contractor's Warranty
If there is any defect in the subject matter of work performed, the party ordering the work may demand that the contractor repair the defect, specifying a reasonable period; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the defect is not significant and excessive costs would be required for the repair.
The party ordering the work may demand compensation for damages in lieu of, or in addition to, the repair of the defect. In such cases, the provisions of Article 533 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
If there is any defect in the subject matter of work performed and the purpose of the contract cannot be achieved because of the defect, the party ordering the work may cancel the contract; provided, however, that this shall not apply to a building or other structure on land.
No Application of Provisions on Contractor's Warranty
The provisions of the preceding two Articles shall not apply if the defect in the subject matter of the work arises due to the nature of the materials supplied by, or instructions given by, the party ordering the work; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the contractor knew that the materials or instructions were inappropriate but did not disclose the same.
Duration of Contractor's Warranty
The demand for repair or claim for damages and cancellation of the contract under the preceding three Articles must be made within one year from the time of the delivery of the subject matter of the work.
Where no delivery of the subject matter is required, the period referred to in the preceding paragraph commences to run from the time of the completion of the work.
A contractor for a building or other structure on land shall be liable for a warranty against defects in the structure or ground for the period of five years from delivery; provided, however, that the period shall be ten years for structures made of stone, earth, bricks, concrete, steel and other similar structures.
If any structure is lost or damaged due to the defects set forth in the preceding paragraph, the party ordering the work must exercise the rights under the provisions of Article 634 within one year from the time of the loss or damage.
Extension of Duration of Warranty
The periods set forth in Article 637 and Paragraph 1 of the preceding Article may be extended by contract so long as they do not exceed the period of time provided for the extinctive prescription under the provisions of Article 167.
Special Agreement of No Warranty
Even if the contractor agrees to a special agreement to the effect that the contractor will not be liable for the warranty provided in Article 634 or Article 635, the contractor may not be released from the contractor's liability with respect to facts the contractor knew and did not disclose.
Cancellation of Contract by Party Ordering Work
The party ordering work may cancel the contract at any time whilst the contractor has not completed the work by compensating any damages. Work)
In cases where the party ordering work is subject to a ruling for the commencement of bankruptcy procedures, the contractor or the trustee in bankruptcy may cancel the contract. In such cases, the contractor may participate in the distribution of the bankrupt estate with respect to remuneration for the work already performed and any costs not included in that remuneration.
In the cases set forth in the preceding paragraph, claims for damages suffered as a result of the cancellation of the contract shall be permitted only for contractors under contracts cancelled by the trustee in bankruptcy. In such cases, the contractors shall participate in the distribution of the bankrupt estate with respect to such damages.

Mandates
Mandates
A mandate shall become effective when one of the parties mandates the other party to perform a juristic act, and the other party accepts the mandate.
Duty of Care of Mandatary
A mandatary shall assume a duty to administer the mandated business with the care of a good manager compliance with the main purport of the mandate.
Reports by Mandatary
A mandatary must, if so requested by the mandator, report the current status of the administration of the mandated business at any time, and must report the process and results without delay upon completion of the mandate.
Delivery of Received Things by Mandatary
The mandatary must deliver to the mandator monies and other Things that he/she has received during the course of administering the mandated business. The same shall apply to fruits the mandatary has reaped.
The mandatary must transfer to the mandator rights the mandatary has acquired in his/her own name on behalf of the mandator.
Mandatary's Responsibility for Consumption of Monies
If the mandatary has consumed monies for his/her personal benefit that the mandatary is to deliver to the mandator, or any monies that are to be used for the benefit of the mandator, the mandatary must pay interest for the period from the day of that consumption. In such cases, if any damages still remain, the mandatary shall be liable to compensate for the same.
Remuneration for Mandatary
In the absence of any special agreements, the mandatary may not claim remuneration from the mandator.
In cases where the mandatary is to receive remuneration, the mandatary may not claim the same until and unless he/she has performed the mandated business; provided, however, that if the remuneration is specified with reference to period, the provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 624 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
If the mandate terminates during performance due to reasons not attributable to the mandatary, the mandatary may demand remuneration in proportion to the performance already completed.
Mandatary's Claims for Advance for Costs
If costs will be incurred in administering the mandated business, the mandator must, at the request of the mandatary, pay an advance for those costs.
Mandatary's Claims for Reimbursement of Expense
If the mandatary has incurred costs found to be necessary for the administration of the mandated business, the mandatary may claim reimbursement of those costs from the mandator and any interest on the same from the day the costs were incurred.
If the mandatary has incurred any obligation found to be necessary for the administration of the mandated business, the mandatary may demand that the mandator perform the obligation on the mandatary's behalf. In such cases, if the obligation has not yet fallen due, the mandatary may require the mandator to tender reasonable security.
If the mandatary suffers any loss due to the administration of the mandated business without negligence in the mandatary, he/she may claim compensation for the loss from the mandator.
Cancellation of Mandate
A mandate may be cancelled by either party at any time.
If one of the parties cancels a mandate at a time that is detrimental to the other party, the former party must compensate the damages suffered by the other party; provided, however, that this shall not apply if there are unavoidable grounds.
Effect of Cancellation of Mandate
The provision of Article 620 shall apply mutatis mutandis to mandates.
Grounds for Termination of Mandate
A mandate shall terminate when: of bankruptcy procedures; guardianship.
Disposition after Termination of Mandate
In cases where a mandate has terminated, if there are pressing circumstances, the mandatary or his/her heir or legal representative must effect necessary dispositions until the time when the mandator or his/her heir or legal representatives is able to take charge of the mandated business.
Requirement for Perfection of Termination of Mandate
The grounds of termination of mandate may not be asserted against the other party unless the other party was notified of or knew of the same.
Quasi-Mandate
The provisions of this Section shall apply mutatis mutandis to mandates of business that do not constitute juristic acts.

Deposits
Deposits
A deposit shall become effective when one of the parties receives a certain Thing by promising that he/she will retain it for the other party.
Use of Deposited Thing and Retention by Third Parties
A depositary may not use, or allow third parties to retain, the Thing deposited without obtaining the consent of the depositor.
The provisions of Article 105 and paragraph 2 of Article 107 shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where a depositary may allow third parties to retain deposited Things.
Duty of Care of Gratuitous Depositary
A person who has undertaken a deposit gratuitously shall assume a duty to retain the Thing deposited exercising care identical to that he/she exercises for his/her own property.
Obligation of Depositary to Give Notice
If a third party asserting rights with respect to the Thing deposited has brought a lawsuit against the depositary, or has effected an attachment, provisional attachment, or provisional disposition, the depositary must notify the depositor of that fact without delay.
Compensation of Damages by Depositor
The depositor must compensate the depositary for damages that occur due to the nature of or defects in the Thing deposited; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the depositor did not, without negligence, know of such nature or defect, or the depositary knew of the same.
Depositor's Demand for Return
Even if the parties specify the time for the return of the Thing deposited, the depositor may demand the return of the same at any time.
Timing of Return of the Thing Deposited
If the parties have not specified the timing of the return of the Thing deposited, the depositary may return the same at any time.
If the timing of the return is specified, the depositary may not return the deposited goods prior to the due date unless there are unavoidable grounds.
Place of Return of the Thing Deposited
The place for the return of the Thing deposited must be at the place where they are to be retained; provided, however, that, if the depositary has changed the place of retention on reasonable grounds, the return may be made at that current place of retention.
Mutatis Mutandis Application of Provisions on Mandate
The provisions of Article 646 to Article 650 (excluding Paragraph 3 of this Article) shall apply mutatis mutandis to deposits.
Deposits for Consumption
The provisions of Section 5 (Loans for Consumption) shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where a depositary may, under the contract, consume the Thing deposited.
Notwithstanding the provisions of Paragraph 1 of Article 591 which shall apply mutatis mutandis under the preceding paragraph, if the contract referred to in the preceding paragraph does not specify the timing of the return, the depositor may demand the return at any time.

Partnerships
Partnership Contracts
A partnership contract shall become effective when each of the parties promises to engage in joint business by making a contribution.
The subject of the contribution may be services .
Joint Ownership in Partnership Property
The contributions of the partners and other partnership property shall be jointly owned by all partners.
Responsibility for Failure to Provide Monetary Contribution
In cases where monies are the subject of the contribution, if any partner fails to contribute his/her share of the contribution, he/she must pay interest on the same and otherwise compensate for damages.
Method of Business Management
The management of partnership business shall be determined by the majority of the partners.
If more than one person is delegated to manage the business referred to in the preceding paragraph under the partnership contract (referred to in the following paragraph as "Operating Officers"), the same shall be determined by majority.
Notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs, the ordinary business of a partnership may be performed by each partner or each Operating Officer individually; provided, however, that this shall not apply if other partners or Operating Officers raise objections prior to the completion of the business.
Mutatis Mutandis Application of Provisions on Mandates
The provisions of Article 646 to Article 650 shall apply mutatis mutandis to partners who manage the business of a partnership.
Resignations and Dismissals of Operating Partners
If one or more partners are delegated to manage partnership business under the partnership contract, those partners may not resign without reasonable grounds.
The partners referred to in the preceding paragraph may be dismissed by the unanimous agreement of the other partners, limited to cases where there are justifiable grounds.
Inspections by Partners of Condition of Partnership Business and Property
Each partner may inspect the condition of the business and property of the partnership even if he/she does not have the right to manage the business of the partnership.
Proportions of Partners' Distributions of Profits and Losses
If partners have not specified the proportions of the distributions of the partnership's profits and losses, the proportions shall be determined in proportion to the value of each partner's contribution.
If the proportions of the distributions are specified solely with respect to either profits or losses, it shall be presumed that the proportions are common to profits and losses.
Exercise of Right of Creditors of the Partnership against Partners
If a creditor of a partnership did not, when his/her claim arose, the proportions of the partners' shares of losses, the creditor may exercise his/her rights against each partner in equal proportions.
Disposal Partners' Shares and Division of Partnership Property
If a partner disposes of his/her share with respect to the partnership property, the disposal may not be asserted against the partnership and third parties who had dealings with the partnership.
A partner may not seek the division of the partnership property before the same is liquidated.
No Set-off by Obligor of Partnership
An obligor of a partnership may not set off his/her obligation against his/her claim against the partners.
Withdrawal of Partners
If a partnership contract does not specify the duration of the partnership, or specifies that the partnership is to continue for the life of a certain partner, each partner may withdraw at any time; provided, however, that, unless there are unavoidable grounds, a partner may not withdraw at a time that is detrimental to the partnership.
Even in cases where the duration of the partnership is specified, each partner may withdraw if there are unavoidable grounds.
In addition to the cases referred to in the preceding Article, partners shall withdraw on the following grounds: procedures; guardianship;
Expulsion of Partners
The expulsion of a partner may be effected by the unanimous agreement of the other partners, limited to cases where there are justifiable grounds; provided, however, that the expulsion may not be asserted against a partner who is expelled unless a notice to that effect is given to that partner.
Refunds of Shares of Withdrawing Partners
Accounts as between the withdrawing partner and other partners must be settled according to the condition of the partnership property as at the time of the withdrawal.
The share of the withdrawing partner may be refunded in money, regardless of the kind of his/her contribution.
With respect to any matter not yet completed at the time of the withdrawal, accounts may be made up subsequent to the completion of that matter.
Causes of Dissolution of Partnerships
A partnership shall be dissolved on the successful completion of the business that is its object, or by the impossibility of such successful completion.
Request for Dissolution of Partnerships
Each partner may request the dissolution of the partnership if there are unavoidable grounds.
Effect of Cancellation of Partnership Contracts
The provisions of Article 620 shall apply mutatis mutandis to partnership contracts.
Liquidation of Partnerships and Appointment of Liquidators
When a partnership is dissolved, the liquidation shall be administered jointly by all partners or by a liquidator appointed by the same.
A liquidator shall be appointed by a majority of all partners.
Method of Management of Liquidators' Business
The provisions of Article 670 shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where there is more than one liquidator.
Resignations and Dismissals of Liquidators who are Partners
The provisions of Article 672 shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where the liquidator is appointed from among the partners under the partnership contract. Assets)
A liquidator shall have the duties to:
The liquidator may perform any and all acts in order to perform its duties listed in the respective items of the preceding paragraph.
Residual assets shall be distributed in proportion to the value of the contributions of each partner.

Life Annuities
Life Annuities
Life annuities shall become effective when one of the parties promises to deliver monies or other Things to the other party or a third party periodically until the death of the first party, the other party or the third party.
Accounting for Life Annuities
Life annuities shall be calculated on a daily basis.
Cancellation of Contracts for Life Annuities
In cases where the obligor in a life annuity has received the principal for the life annuity, if the obligor fails to pay the life annuity or fails to perform other obligations, the other party may demand the return of the principal. In such cases, the other party must return the amount of the life annuity he/she has already received to the obligor of the life annuity, less the amount of the interest on that principal.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude claims for damages.
Cancellation of Contracts for Life Annuities and Simultaneous Performance
The provisions of Article 533 shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases referred to in the preceding Article.
Declaration of Continuation of Claim for Life Annuity
If a death provided for in Article 689 occurs due to grounds attributable to the obligor in a life annuity, the court may, at the request of the obligee in the life annuity or the obligee's heirs, declare that the life annuity claim shall continue for a reasonable period.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the exercise of the rights provided in Article 691.
Testamentary Gifts of Life Annuities
The provisions of this Section shall apply mutatis mutandis to testamentary gifts of life annuities.

Settlements
Settlements
A settlement shall become effective when the parties to a dispute promise to settle the dispute through reciprocal concessions.
Effect of Settlements
In cases where it is admitted at settlement that one of the parties has the rights that are the subject of the dispute, or that the other party did not have the rights, if conclusive evidence is obtained to the effect that the first party did not have the rights in the past, or that the other party did have the rights, the rights are regarded as either transferred to the first party or extinguished at settlement.


Negotiorum Gestio (Management of Business))
Negotiorum Gestio Management of Business
A person who commences the management of a business for another person without being obligated to do so (hereinafter in this Chapter referred to as "Manager") must manage that business (hereinafter referred to as "Management of Business") in accordance with the nature of the business, using the method that best conforms to the interests of that another person
The Manager must engage in Management of Business in accordance with the intentions of the principal if the Manager knows, or is able to conjecture that intention.
Urgent Management of Business
If a Manager engages in the Management of Business in order to allow a principal to escape imminent danger to the principal's person, reputation or property, the Manager shall not be liable to compensate for damages resulting from the same unless he/she has acted in bad faith or with gross negligence.
Obligation of Managers to Give Notice
A Manager must notify the principal that the Manager has commenced the Management of Business; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the principal already knows of the same.
Continuation of Management of Business by Managers
A Manager must continue the Management of Business until the principal or his/her heirs or legal representatives can undertake it; provided, however, that this shall not apply in cases where it is evident that the continuation of the Management of Business is contrary to the intentions of the principal, or is disadvantageous to the principal.
Mutatis Mutandis Application of Provisions on Mandates
The provisions from Article 645 through to Article 647 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the Management of Business.
Managers' Claims for Reimbursement of Costs
If a Manager has incurred useful expenses for a principal, the Manager may claim reimbursement of those costs from the principal.
The provisions of Paragraph 2 of Article 650 shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where a Manager has incurred useful obligations on behalf of the principal.
If a Manager has engaged in the Management of Business against the intention of the principal, the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall apply mutatis mutandis, solely to the extent the principal is actually enriched.


Unjust Enrichment
Obligation to Return Unjust Enrichment
A person who has benefited (hereinafter in this Chapter referred to as "beneficiary") from the property or labor of others without legal cause and has thereby caused loss to others shall assume an obligation to return that benefit, to the extent the benefit exists.
Obligation of Beneficiaries in Bad Faith to Return
A Beneficiary in bad faith must return the benefit received together with interest thereon. In such cases, if any damages still remain, the Beneficiary shall be liable to compensate for the same.
Performance knowing of Absence of Obligation
A person who has tendered anything as performance of an obligation may not demand the return of the thing tendered if the person knew, at the time, that the obligation did not exist.
Performance before Due Date
If an obligor has tendered anything as performance of an obligation that has not yet fallen due, the obligor may not demand the return of the thing tendered; provided, however, that, if the obligor tendered anything by mistake, the obligee must return the benefit gained as a result.
Performance of Obligations of Others
In cases where a person who is not an obligor has performed an obligation by mistake, if the obligee has, in good faith, allowed the instrument to be lost, damaged the instrument, waived the security or lost the claim by prescription, the person who performed the obligation may not demand the return of the performance.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the person who performed an obligation from exercising his/her right of subrogation against the obligor.
Performance for Illegal Causes
A person who has tendered performance of an obligation for an illegal cause may not demand the return of the thing tendered; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the illegal cause existed solely in relation to the Beneficiary.


Torts
Damages in Torts
A person who has intentionally or negligently infringed any right of others, or legally protected interest of others, shall be liable to compensate any damages resulting in consequence.
Compensation for Damages Other than Property
Persons liable for damages under the provisions of the preceding Article must also compensate for damages other than those to property, regardless of whether the body, liberty or reputation of others have been infringed, or property rights of others have been infringed.
Compensation for Damages to Next of Kin
A person who has taken the life of another must compensate for damages to the father, mother, spouse and children of the victim, even in cases where the property rights of the same have not been infringed.
Capacity for Liability
In cases where a minor has inflicted damages on others, if the minor does not have sufficient intellectual capacity to appreciate his/her liability for his/her own act, the minor shall not be liable to compensate for that act.
A person who has inflicted damages on others while he/she lacks the capacity to appreciate his/her liability for his/her own act due to mental disability shall not be liable to compensate for the same; provided, however, that this shall not apply if he/she has temporarily invited that condition, intentionally or negligently.
Liability of Person Obligated to Supervise a Person without Capacity
In cases where a person without capacity to assume liability is not liable in accordance with the provisions of the preceding two Articles, the person with the legal obligation to supervise the person without capacity to assume liability shall be liable to compensate for damages that the person without capacity to assume liability has inflicted on a third party; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the person who has the obligation to supervise did not fail to perform his/her obligation or if the damages could not have been avoided even if he/she had not failed to perform his/her obligation.
A person who supervises a person without capacity to assume liability, on behalf of a person who has the obligation to supervise, shall also assume the liability under the preceding paragraph.
Liability of Employers
A person who employs others for a certain business shall be liable for damages inflicted on a third party by his/her employees with respect to the execution of that business; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the employer exercised reasonable care in appointing the employee or in supervising the business, or if the damages could not have been avoided even if he/she had exercised reasonable care.
A person who supervises the business on behalf of the employer shall also assume the liability under the preceding paragraph.
The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall not preclude the employer or supervisor from exercising their right to obtain reimbursement against the employee.
Liability of Party Ordering Work
A party ordering work shall not be liable for the damages a contractor inflicted on a third party with respect to his/her work; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the party ordering work is negligent in his/her order or instructions.
Liability of Possessor and Owner of Structure on Land
If any defect in the installation or preservation of any structure on land causes damages to others, the possessor of such structure shall be liable to the victims to compensate for those damages; provided, however, that, if the possessor has used necessary care to prevent the damages arising, the owner must compensate for the damages.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where there is any defect in the planting or support of bamboos and trees.
In the cases of the preceding two paragraphs, if there is another person who is liable for the cause of the damages, the possessor or owner may exercise their right to obtain reimbursement against such person.
Liability of Possessor of Animal
A possessor of an animal shall be liable to compensate for the damages that the animal has inflicted on others; provided, however, that this shall not apply if he/she managed the animal with reasonable care according to the kind and nature of the animal.
A person who manages the animal on behalf of the possessor shall also assume the liability under the preceding paragraph.
Liability of Joint Tortfeasors
If more than one person has inflicted damages on others by their joint tortious acts, each of them shall be jointly and severally liable to compensate for those damages. The same shall apply if it cannot be ascertained which of the joint tortfeasors inflicted the damages.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply to any person who incited or was an accessory to the perpetrator, by deeming him/her to be one of the joint tortfeasors.
Self-Defense and Aversion of Present Danger
A person who, in response to the tortious act of another, unavoidably commits a harmful act to protect himself/herself, the rights of a third party, or any legally protected interest, shall not be liable for damages; provided, however, that the victim shall not be precluded from claiming damages against the person who committed the tortious act.
The provisions of the preceding paragraph shall apply mutatis mutandis to cases where a Thing belonging to others is damaged to avoid imminent danger arising from that Thing. for Damages)
An unborn child shall be deemed to have been already born with respect to the right to demand compensation for damages.
Method of Damages and Comparative Negligence
The provisions of Article 417 shall apply mutatis mutandis to compensation for damages in tort.
If a victim is negligent, the court may determine the amount of compensation by taking that factor into consideration.
Recovery in Defamation
The court may, at the request of the victim, order a person who defamed others, to effect appropriate measures to restore the reputation of the victim in lieu of, or in addition to, damages.
Restriction of Period of Right to Demand Compensation for Damages in Tort
The right to demand compensation for damages in tort shall be extinguished by the operation of prescription if it is not exercised by the victim or his/her legal representative within three years from the time when he/she comes to know of the damages and the identity of the perpetrator. The same shall apply when twenty years have elapsed from the time of the tortious act.
</DOC>
<DOC>
<DOCNO>IV</DOCNO>
Relatives
General Provisions
Range of Relatives
The following persons shall be relatives
Determining Degree of kinship
The degree of kinship between two relatives shall be determined by counting the number of generations between them.
The degree of kinship between collateral relatives shall be determined by counting the number of generations between a person or his/her spouse up to a common ancestor and back down to the other person.
Relationship through Adoption
From the time of adoption, the relationship between an adopted child and an adoptive parent (and his/her relative by blood) shall be deemed to be the same as that between relatives by blood.
End of Relationship by Affinity by Divorce etc.
The relationship between relatives by affinity shall come to an end by divorce.
The same shall apply in the case where a spouse has died and the surviving spouse indicates an intention to end the relationship between relatives by affinity.
End of Adoptive Relation by Dissolution
The relationship of an adopted child, his/her spouse, any of his/her lineal descendants and their spouses with an adoptive parent and his/her spouse shall come to an end by dissolution of adoptive relation.
Mutual Help between Relatives
Lineal relatives by blood and relatives who live together shall help one another.


Marriage
Formation of Marriage
Requirements for Marriage
Marriageable Age
A man who has attained 18 years of age, and a woman who has attained 16 years of age may enter into marriage.
Prohibition of Bigamy
A person who has a spouse shall not enter into another marriage.
Period of Prohibition of Remarriage
A woman may not remarry unless six months have passed since the day of dissolution or rescission of her previous marriage.
In the case where a woman had conceived a child before the cancellation or dissolution of her previous marriage, the provision of the preceding paragraph shall not apply.
Prohibition of Marriage between Close Relatives
Neither lineal relatives by blood nor collateral relatives by blood within the third degree of kinship may marry; provided that this shall not apply between an adopted child and his/her collateral relatives by blood through adoption.
The preceding paragraph shall also apply after the termination of a family relationship pursuant to the provision of Article 817-9.
Prohibition of Marriage between Lineal Relatives by Affinity
Lineal relatives by affinity may not marry. This shall also apply after the termination of a relationship by affinity pursuant to the provisions of Article 728 or Article 817-9.
Prohibition of Marriage between Adoptive Parent and Child etc.
Even after the termination of a family relationship pursuant to the provision of Article 729, an adopted child or spouse of adopted child, or a lineal descendant or spouse of a lineal descendant, may not marry an adoptive parent or his/her lineal ascendant.
Parental Consent for Marriage of Minor
A minor shall obtain the consent of both parents to marry.
If one parent does not consent, the consent of the other parent is sufficient. This shall also apply if one parent is unknown, has died, or is unable to indicate his/her intent.
Marriage of Adult Ward
An adult ward does not require the consent of his/her guardian of adult to marry.
Notification of Marriage
Marriage shall take effect upon notification pursuant to the Family Registration Act (Act No. 224 of 1947).
The notification in the preceding paragraph shall be given by document with the signatures of both parties and not less than two adult witnesses, or given orally by these persons.
Acceptance of Notification of Marriage
Notification of marriage may not be accepted unless it has been found not to violate the provisions of Articles 731 to 737 inclusive, the provision of paragraph (2) of the preceding Article, or the provisions of any other laws and regulations.
Marriage between Japanese Nationals in Foreign Country
Two Japanese nationals in a foreign country who intend to marry may give notification to the Japanese ambassador a minister of legation or consul stationed in that country. In this case, the provisions of the preceding two Articles shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Void and Annulled Marriages
Grounds on Which Marriage is Void
Marriage shall be void only in the following cases:
Rescission of Marriage
Marriage may not be annulled, unless pursuant to the provisions of Articles 744 to 747 inclusive.
Rescission of Unlawful Marriage
Either of the parties, their relatives, or a public prosecutor may make a claim to the family court to rescind a marriage if it violates the provisions of Articles 731 to 736 inclusive; provided, however, that a public prosecutor may not claim this after the death of one of the parties.
A spouse or previous spouse of a party to a marriage that violates the provisions of Article 732 or Article 733 may claim for rescission of marriage.
rescission of Marriage in Violation of Marriageable Age
When a person of non-marriageable age reaches marriageable age, a claim for rescission of a marriage that violates the provisions of Article 731 may not be made.
A person of non-marriageable age may claim rescission of marriage within a further three months after he/she has reached marriageable age; provided that this shall not apply if he/she has ratified the marriage after reaching marriageable age.
Rescission of Marriage Formed within the Period of Prohibition of Remarriage
A claim for rescission may not be made for a marriage that violates the provisions of Article 733 if six months have passed from the day on which the previous marriage was cancelled or rescinded, or if a woman has conceived a child after remarriage.
Rescission of Marriage by Fraud or Duress
A person who has married due to fraud or duress may make a claim for rescission of marriage to the family court.
The claim for rescission of marriage pursuant to the preceding paragraph lapses upon the passage of three months after the party has discovered the fraud or escaped the duress, or upon ratification.
Effect of Rescission of Marriage
Rescission of marriage shall not have retroactive effect.
A party who did not know of the cause of rescission at the time of marriage must return property obtained by the marriage to the extent of the gain he/she actually receives.
A party who was aware of the cause of rescission at the time of marriage must return all of the gain obtained by the marriage. In this case, the party is liable to compensate an adverse party without knowledge for damages.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Divorce Provisions
The provisions of paragraph (1) of Article 728, Articles 766 to 769 inclusive, the proviso to paragraph (1) of Article 790, and paragraphs (2),(3),(5) and (6) of Article 819 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the rescission of marriage.

Effect of Marriage
Surname of Husband and Wife
A husband and wife shall adopt the surname of the husband or wife in accordance with that which is decided at the time of marriage.
Surviving Spouse Reverting to Previous Surname etc.
If a husband or wife dies, the surviving spouse may revert to using the surname he/she used before marriage.
The provisions of Article 769 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the preceding paragraph and to the case referred to in paragraph (2) of Article 728.
Duty to Live Together, Cooperate, and Provide Mutual Assistance
A husband and wife shall live together and provide mutual cooperation and assistance.
Constructive Adult by Marriage
If a minor enters into marriage, he/she shall be deemed to have attained majority.
Right to Rescind Contract between Husband and Wife
Either husband or wife may at any time during marriage rescind a contract between husband and wife; provided, however, that this may not harm the rights of a third party.

Marital Property
General Provisions
Marital Property of Husband and Wife
The property rights and duties of a husband and wife shall be prescribed by the following subsections, unless they entered into a contract setting forth otherwise, regarding their property before giving notification of the marriage.
Requirements of Perfection of Contract on Property of Husband and Wife
If a husband and wife have entered into a contract that departs from the statutory property system, the contract may not be asserted against the successor in title of the husband or wife, or a third party unless registered prior to notification of marriage.
Limitations on Altering Property Rights of Husband and Wife etc.
The property rights of a husband and wife may not be altered after notification of marriage.
In the case where one party to a marriage administers property and that property is imperiled by misadministration, the other party may make a claim to the family court for his own administration over that property.
A claim may be made for division of property held in co-ownership together with the claim referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Requirements of Perfection of Change of the Administrator of Property or Division of Property in Co-ownership
If an administrator of property has been changed, or property held in co-ownership has been divided pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article or as a result of the contract referred to in Article 755, this may not be asserted against the successor in title of the husband or wife, or a third party unless it is registered.
Statutory Marital Property System
Sharing of Living Expenses
A husband and wife shall share the expenses that arise from the marriage taking into account their property, income, and all other circumstances.
Joint and Several Liability for Debts incurred for Household Necessities
If one party to a marriage engages in a juristic act with a third party regarding everyday household matters, the other party shall be jointly and severally liable for debts that arise from that act; provided that this shall not apply if prior notice is given to the third party to the effect that the other party will not assume such liability.
Ownership of Property between Husband and Wife
Property owned by one party before marriage and property obtained in the name of that party during marriage shall be separate property (property owned singularly by one party to a marriage).
Property that does not clearly belong to either husband or wife shall be presumed to be held in co-ownership.

Divorce
Divorce by Agreement
Divorce by Agreement
A husband and wife may divorce by agreement.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Marriage Provisions
The provisions of Articles 738, 739, and 747 shall apply mutatis mutandis to divorce by agreement.
Acceptance of Notification of Divorce
Notification of divorce may not be accepted unless the divorce has been found not to violate the provision of paragraph (2) of Article 739 applied mutatis mutandis to the preceding Article, paragraph (1) of Article 819, or the provisions of any other laws and regulations.
If notification of divorce has been accepted despite the violation of the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the effect of the divorce shall not be prevented because of this violation.
Determination of Matters regarding Custody of Child after Divorce etc.
If parents divorce by agreement, the matters of who will have custody over a child, visitation and other contacts between the father or mother and the child, sharing of expenses required for custody of the child and any other necessary matters regarding custody over the child shall be determined by that agreement. In this case, the child's interests shall be considered with the highest priority.
If the agreement set forth in the preceding paragraph has not been made, or cannot be made, the matters set forth in the preceding paragraph shall be determined by the family court.
The family court may change the agreement or determination under the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs and order any other proper disposition regarding custody over the child, if it finds this necessary.
The rights and duties of parents beyond the scope of custody may not be altered by the provisions of the preceding three paragraphs.
Reversion to Previous Surname by Divorce
The surname of a husband or wife who has taken a new name by marriage shall revert to the surname used before marriage by divorce by agreement.
A husband or wife whose surname has reverted to the surname before marriage pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph may use the surname he/she used at the time of divorce by notification pursuant to the Family Registration Act within three months of the time of divorce.
Distribution of Property
One party to a divorce by agreement may claim a distribution of property from the other party.
If the parties do not, or cannot, settle on agreement with regard to the distribution of property pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph, either party may make a claim to the family court for a disposition in lieu of agreement; provided that this claim for distribution of property shall be extinguished at the expiration of two years from the day of divorce.
In the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, the family court shall determine whether to make a distribution, and the amount and method of that distribution, taking into account the amount of property obtained through the cooperation of both parties and all other circumstances.
Assumption of Rights upon Reversion to Previous Surname by Divorce
If a husband or wife who has taken a new surname by marriage divorces by agreement after inheriting the rights contained in paragraph (1) of Article 897, the matter of who will be the successor of those rights shall be determined by agreement of the parties and any other interested persons.
If the agreement of the preceding paragraph is not, or cannot be, made, the family court shall determine who will be the successor of the rights in that paragraph.
Judicial Divorce
Judicial Divorce
Only in the cases stated in the following items may either husband or wife file a suit for divorce:
A court may dismiss a suit for divorce if it finds continuing the marriage reasonable taking into account all circumstances, even in the case where there is a cause listed in items (i) to (iv) inclusive of the preceding paragraph.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Divorce by Agreement Provisions
The provisions of Articles 766 to 769 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case of judicial divorce.


Parent and Child
Natural Children
Presumption of Child in Wedlock
A child conceived by a wife during marriage shall be presumed to be a child of her husband.
A child born after 200 days from the formation of marriage or within 300 days of the day of the dissolution or rescission of marriage shall be presumed to have been conceived during marriage.
Determination of Paternity by Court
In the case where a woman gives birth in violation of the provisions of paragraph (1) of Article 733, if the paternity of the child cannot be determined pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article, the court shall determine paternity of the child.
Rebutting Presumption of Legitimacy
Under the circumstances described in Article 772, a husband may rebut the presumption of the child in wedlock.
Action to Rebut Presumption of Legitimacy
The father's right to rebut the presumption of child in wedlock under Article 774 shall be exercised by an action of denial of child in wedlock against the child or a mother who has parental authority. If there is no mother who has parental authority, the family court shall appoint a special representative.
Recognition of Legitimacy
If a husband recognizes that a child is his child in wedlock after the birth of the child, he shall lose his right to rebut the presumption of legitimacy.
Limitation upon Action of Rebutting Presumption
A husband shall bring an action to rebut the presumption of the child in wedlock within one year of knowing of the child's birth.
If the husband is an adult ward, the period of Article 777 shall begin from the time the husband knew of the child's birth after the rescission of an order for commencement of guardianship.
Affiliation
A father or a mother may affiliate his/her child out of wedlock.
Competency for Affiliation
A father or a mother does not require the consent of a legal representative for affiliation, even if he/she is a minor or an adult ward.
Method of Affiliation
Affiliation shall be made through notification pursuant to the provisions of the Family Registration Act.
Affiliation may also be made by will.
Affiliation of Adult Child
A father or mother may not affiliate his/her adult child without that adult child's consent.
Affiliation of Unborn Child or Child who has Died
A father may also affiliate his unborn child. In this case, the mother's consent shall be obtained.
If a child has died, a father or mother may still give affiliation, limited to the case where that child had a lineal descendant. In this case, if that lineal descendant is an adult, his/her consent shall be obtained.
Effect of Affiliation
Affiliation has retroactive effect from the time of birth; provided that this shall not prejudice a right already acquired by a third party.
Prohibition of Rescission of Affiliation
A father or a mother who has given affiliation may not rescind that affiliation.
Assertion of Opposing Facts against Affiliation
A child or any other interested person may assert opposing facts against an affiliation.
Action for Affiliation
A child, his/her lineal descendant, or the legal representative of either, may bring an action for affiliation; provided that this shall not apply if three years have passed since the day of the death of the parent.
Determination of Matters with Regard to Custody of Child after Affiliation etc.
In the case where a father gives affiliation, the provisions of Article 766 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Legitimation
By the marriage of his/her mother and father, a child affiliated by his/her father shall acquire the status of a child in wedlock.
A child affiliated by his/her parents while they are married shall acquire the status of a child in wedlock from the time of that affiliation.
The provisions of the preceding two paragraphs shall apply mutatis mutandis in the case where a child has already died.
Child's Surname
A child in wedlock shall take the surname of his/her parents; provided that if the parents divorce before the child is born, the child shall take the surname of his/her parents at the time of divorce.
A child out of wedlock shall take the surname of his/her mother.
Change of Child's Surname
In the case where a child's surname differs from that of his/her father or mother, he/she may take the name of his/her father or mother by notification pursuant to the provisions of the Family Registration Act after having obtained the family court's permission.
In the case where a child's surname differs from that of his/her parents due to his/her father or mother taking a new surname, he/she may take the name of his/her parents, if they are married, without obtaining the permission referred to in the preceding paragraph by notification pursuant to the provisions of the Family Registration Act.
If a child has not attained 15 years of age, his/her legal representative may perform the acts referred to in the preceding two paragraphs on his/her behalf.
A minor who has taken a new surname pursuant to the provisions of the preceding three paragraphs may revert to using his/her previous surname within one year of attaining majority by notification pursuant to the provisions of the Family Registration Act.

Adoption
Requirements for Adoption
Age of Adoptive Parent
A person who has attained the age of majority may adopt another as his/her child.
Prohibition of Adopting Ascendant or Person of Greater Age
Neither an ascendant nor a person of greater age may be adopted.
Adoption of Ward by Guardian
Where a guardian adopts a ward (here and below, referring to a minor ward and an adult ward), he/she shall obtain the permission of the family court. The same shall apply in the case where the guardianship has ceased but the account of administration of the property has not been settled.
Adoption of Minor by Married Person
A married person shall adopt a minor only jointly with the spouse; provided, however, that this shall not apply in cases where he/she adopts a child in wedlock of his/her spouse or his/her spouse is incapable of indicating her/his intention.
Adoption by Married Person
A married person shall only adopt or be adopted by another with the consent of his/her spouse,; provided, however, that this shall not apply in the case he/she adopts or is adopted with his/her spouse jointly, or his/her spouse is incapable of indicating her/his intention.
Adoption of Person under 15 years of age
If a person to be adopted has not attained 15 years of age, his/her legal representative may give his/her consent to the adoption of that person on behalf of that person.
Where a person to be adopted is cared for by one of his/her parents and that parent does not have parental authority in relation to the person but cares for the person in accordance with Article 766, a legal representative shall obtain the consent of that parent before giving the consent referred to in the preceding paragraph. The same shall apply in the case where one of said person's parents has parental authority in relation to the person which is suspended.
Adoption of Minor
Where a person to be adopted is a minor, the permission of the family court shall be obtained; provided that this shall not apply in the cases where the person to be adopted is a lineal descendant of either the adoptive parent or the adoptive parent's spouse.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Marriage Provisions
The provisions of Article 738 and Article 739 shall apply mutatis mutandis to adoption.
Acceptance of Notification of Adoption
No notification of adoption shall be accepted until it has been found that the adoption does not violate any of the provisions of Articles 792 to 799 inclusive or the provisions of any other laws and regulations.
Formalities for Adoption between Japanese Nationals in Foreign Country
If a Japanese national in a foreign country intends to adopt, or to be adopted by , another Japanese national in that country, notification of adoption may be made to the Japanese ambassador, minister or consul acting in that country. In this case, the provisions of Article 739 applied mutatis mutandis to Article 799 and the provision of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis.
Nullity and Rescission of Adoption
Nullity of Adoption
Adoption shall be void only on the following grounds:
Rescission of Adoption
Adoption shall only be annulled pursuant to the provisions of Articles 804 to 808 inclusive.
Rescission of Adoption Where Adoptive Parent Is Minor
An adoptive parent or his/her legal representative may petition the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provision of Article 792; provided that this shall not apply in the cases where six months have passed from the time the adoptive parent attains the age of majority or he/she has ratified the adoption.
Rescission of Adoption Where Adoptive Parent is Ascendant or of Greater Age
Either of the parties to an adoption or any relative of them may apply to the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provision of Article 793.
Rescission of Adoption between Guardian and Ward not Assented to by the Family Court
An adopted child or any natural relative of the child may apply to the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provisions of Article 794; provided, however, that this shall not apply after the account of administration has been settled if the adopted child ratifies the adoption or if six months have passed since settlement.
No ratification in the proviso to the preceding paragraph shall take effect, unless the adopted child ratified the adoption after he/she had attained the age of majority or had recovered legal capacity to act.
Where the account has been settled but the adopted child has not attained the age of majority or has not recovered legal capacity to act, the period referred to in the proviso to paragraph (1) shall be calculated from the time the adopted child attains the age of majority or recovers legal capacity to act.
Rescission of Adoption Without Spousal Consent etc.
A person who does not give his/her consent to an adoption may apply to the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provisions of Article 796; provided that this shall not apply in the cases where six months have passed from the time the person had knowledge of the adoption or he/she ratified the adoption.
A person who gave the consent referred to in Article 796 by fraud or duress may apply to the family court for rescission of the adoption; provided that this shall not apply in cases where six months have passed from the time the person had knowledge of fraud or escaped from duress, or the person ratified the adoption.
Rescission of Adoption made without Consent of Person Who Cares for Child etc.
A person who does not give his/her consent to the adoption may apply to the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provision of paragraph (2) of Article 797; provided that this shall not apply if the person has ratified the adoption, or if, after the adopted child has reached 15 years of age, six months have passed or the child has ratified the adoption.
The provisions of paragraph (2) of the preceding Article shall apply mutatis mutandis to the consent referred to in paragraph (2) of Article 797 made due to fraud or duress.
Rescission of Adoption of Minor not Assented to by Family Court
An adopted child, any natural relative of the child, or a person who gave his/her consent to the adoption on the adopted child's behalf may apply to the family court for rescission of an adoption that violates the provisions of Article 798; provided, however, that this shall not apply if, after the adopted child attains majority, six months have passed or he/she has ratified the adoption.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Provisions regarding rescission of Marriage etc.
The provisions of Article 747 and Article 748 shall apply mutatis mutandis to adoption. In this case, 'three months' in paragraph (2) of Article 747 shall be read as 'six months'.
The provisions of Article 769 and Article 816 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the rescission of adoption.
Effect of Adoption
Acquisition of Status of Child in wedlock
An adopted child acquires the status of a child in wedlock of his/her adoptive parent(s) from the time of adoption.
Surname of Adopted Child
An adopted child shall take the surname of his/her adoptive parent(s); provided that this shall not apply to an adopted child who has changed his/her surname by marriage and continues to use the surname determined at the time of marriage.
Dissolution of Adoptive Relations
Dissolution of Adoptive Relations by Agreement etc.
Parties to an adoption may agree to dissolve the adoptive relationship.
If an adopted child is under 15 years of age, an adoptive parent and a person to be a legal representative of the child after the dissolution of adoptive relation may agree to dissolve the adoptive relation.
If, in the case referred to in the preceding paragraph, the parents of the adopted child divorce, they may agree that one of them should have parental authority with respect to the child after the dissolution of adoptive relation.
If the parents of the adopted child do not, or cannot, make the agreement referred to in the preceding paragraph, the family court may, at the request of a father, a mother, or an adoptive parent referred to in that paragraph, make a ruling in lieu of the agreement.
If there is no person to be a legal representative of the adopted child for the purposes of paragraph (2), the family court may, at the request of any relative of the adopted child or any other interested party, appoint a person to be a guardian of a minor for the adopted child after the dissolution of adoptive relation.
If one of the parties to an adoption has died and the surviving party intends to dissolve the adoptive relation, he/she may do so with the permission of the family court.
Dissolution of Adoptive relation Between Married Couple and Minor
Where adoptive parents who are married to each other intend to dissolve the adoptive relation with a minor, they shall do so jointly; provided, however, that this shall not apply if one of them is incapable of indicating his/her intention.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Marriage Provisions
The provisions of Article 738, Article 739, and Article 747 shall apply mutatis mutandis to dissolution of adoptive relation. In this case, 'three months' in paragraph (2) of Article 747 shall be read as 'six months'.
Acceptance of Notification of Dissolution of Adoptive Relation
No notification of dissolution of adoptive relation shall be accepted until it has been found not to violate any of the provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 739 applied mutatis mutandis to the preceding Article, Article 811 and Article 811-2, or the provisions of any other laws and regulations.
Where the notification of dissolution of adoptive relation has been accepted in violation of the provisions of the preceding paragraph, the dissolution is not prevented from taking effect due to the violation.
Judicial Dissolution of Adoptive Relation
Either of the parties to an adoption may, in the following cases only, bring an action for dissolution of adoptive relation:
The provision of paragraph (2) of Article 770 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases listed in item (i) and item (ii) of the preceding paragraph.
Party to Action for Dissolution of Adoptive Relation When Adopted Child below 15 years of age
If an adopted child has not attained 15 years of age, a person who may make an agreement with the adoptive parent(s) to dissolve the adoptive relation pursuant to the provisions of Article 811 may bring or be subject to an action for dissolution of adoptive relation.
Resumption of Surname by Dissolution of Adoptive Relation
An adopted child shall resume using the surname he/she used before the adoption by dissolution of adoptive relation; provided that this shall not apply where a married person adopted another as his/her child with his/her spouse jointly and the adopted child dissolved the adoptive relation with only one of adoptive parents.
If a person resumes using the name h/she used before the adoption pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph after seven years have passed since the time of adoption, he/she may take the surname used at the time of dissolution of adoptive relation by giving notification, pursuant to the provisions of the Family Registration Act, within three months of the day of dissolution.
Assumption of Rights upon Resumption of Surname by Dissolution of Adoptive Relations
The provisions of Article 769 shall apply mutatis mutandis to dissolution of adoptive relations.
Special Adoption
Making of Special Adoption
The family court may, at the request of a person to be an adoptive parent, make a ruling establishing an adoption which extinguishes the legal relationship between a child and his/her natural relatives (referred to in this subsection as 'special adoption').
The permission referred to in Article 794 and Article 798 is not required for the application referred to in the provision of the preceding paragraph.
Joint Adoption by Married Couple
A person to be an adoptive parent shall be a married person.
If one spouse does not become an adoptive parent, the other spouse may not be an adoptive parent; provided, however, that this shall not apply if that spouse intends to adopt a child in wedlock of the other spouse (excluding an adopted child who is not the subject of a special adoption ruling).
Age of Person to be Adoptive Parent
A person who has not attained 25 years of age may not be an adoptive parent; provided that this shall not apply if one spouse of a married couple to be adoptive parents has attained 20 years of age but has not attained 25 years of age.
Age of Person to be Adopted Child
No person who has attained 6 years of age at the time of the application referred to in the provisions of Article 817-2 shall be adopted; provided that this shall not apply if he/she has not attained 8 years of age and has been continually cared for by a person to be an adoptive parent since before the child attained 6 years of age.
Parental Consent
A ruling of special adoption shall only be made if both parents of a person to be adopted gives his/her consent to the special adoption; provided that this shall not apply in cases where the parents are incapable of indicating their intention or the parents have abused the child, abandoned the child without reasonable cause, or there is any other cause of grave harm to the interests of the person to become the adopted child.
Necessity Especially for the Interests of the Child
A ruling of special adoption shall only be made if both parents of a person to be adopted are incapable or unfit to care for the child or there are any other special circumstances, and it is found that the special adoption is especially necessary for the interests of the child.
Circumstances of Care
In making a ruling of special adoption, the circumstances of not less than six months of the care given by the person(s) to become adoptive parent(s) over the person to become the adopted child shall be considered.
The period in the preceding paragraph shall be calculated from the time of the application referred to in the provisions of Article 817-2; provided that this shall not apply if the circumstances of care are evident prior to the application.
Extinguishment of Legal Relationship with Natural Relatives
The legal relationship between an adopted child and his/her natural parents and relative by bloods shall be extinguished by a ruling of special adoption; provided that this shall not apply to the legal relationship with the other party referred to in the provision of the proviso to paragraph (2) of Article 817-3 and his/her relative by bloods.
Dissolution of Special Adoption
The family court may, at the request of the adopted child, his/her natural parents or a public prosecutor, make a ruling dissolving the adoptive relation, if both of the following items are satisfied and the family court finds it especially necessary for the interests of the adopted child:
Dissolution of special adoption shall only be made pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph.
Restoration of Legal Relationship with Natural Relatives by Dissolution of Adoptive Relation
The same legal relationship that was extinguished by the special adoption shall arise between an adopted child and his/her natural parents and their relatives by blood from the time of dissolution of adoptive relation.


Parental Authority
General Provisions
Person Who Has Parental Authority
A child who has not attained the age of majority shall be subject to the parental authority of his/her parents.
If a child is an adopted child, he/she shall be subject to the parental authority of his/her adoptive parents.
Parental authority shall be exercised jointly by married parents; provided that if either parent is incapable of exercising parental authority, the other parent shall do so.
Person Who Has Parental Authority in the Case of Divorce or Recognition
If parents divorce by agreement, they may agree upon which parent shall have parental authority in relation to a child.
In the case of judicial divorce, the court shall determine which parent shall have parental authority.
In the case where parents divorce before the birth of a child, the mother shall exercise parental rights and duties; provided that the parties may agree that the father shall have parental authority after the child is born.
A father shall only exercise parental authority with regard to a child of his that he has affiliated if both parents agree that he shall have parental authority.
When the parents do not, or cannot, make the agreements referred to in paragraph (1), paragraph (3), and the preceding paragraph, the family court may, at the request of the father or the mother, make a ruling in lieu of agreement.
The family court may, at the request of any relative of the child, rule that the other parent shall have parental authority in relation to the child if it finds it necessary for the interests of the child.

Effect of Parental Authority
Right and Duty of Care and Education
A person who exercises parental authority holds the right, and bears the duty, to care for and educate the child for the child's interests.
Determination of Residence
Residence of a child shall be determined by a person who exercises parental authority.
Discipline
A person who exercises parental authority may discipline the child to the extent necessary for the care and education under the provisions of Article 820.
Permission for Occupation
A child may not have an occupation without the permission of a person who exercises parental authority.
A person who exercises parental authority may revoke or limit the permission referred to in the preceding paragraph in the case referred to in paragraph (2) of Article 6.
Administration and Representation over Property
A person who exercises parental authority shall administer the property of the child and represent the child in any legal juristic act in respect of the child's property; provided, however, that if an obligation requiring an act of the child is to be created, the consent of the child shall be obtained.
Effect of Acts Done by One Parent in the Name of Both Parents
Where parents exercise parental authority jointly and one parent, in the name of both parents, performs a juristic act on behalf of a child, or give his/her consent for the child to perform a juristic act, the effect of that act shall not be prevented, even if it is contrary to the intention of the other parent; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the other party has knowledge.
Conflict of Interest
If an act involves a conflict of interest between a father or mother who exercises parental authority and a child, a person who exercises parental authority shall apply to the family court to have a special representative for the child appointed.
In the case where a person exercises parental authority for more than one child, if there is an act which involves a conflict of interest between one child and the other child or children, a person who exercises parental authority shall apply to have a special representative for that child appointed.
Duty of Care in Administration of Property
A person who exercises parental authority shall exercise the right of administration of property with the same care he/she would exercise for him/herself.
Accounts of Administration of Property
When a child attains the age of majority, a person who exercised parental authority shall account for the administration of property without delay; provided, however, that the expenses incurred in the care of the child and the administration of property shall be deemed to have been set-off against the profits from the child's property.
If a third party who has granted property to a child gratuitously indicates a contrary intention, the provision of the proviso to the preceding Article shall not apply to that property.
Administration of Property Given to Child by Third Party Gratuitously
If a third party who grants property to a child gratuitously indicates an intention not to allow a father or mother who exercises parental authority to administer that property, that property shall not be subject to the administration of the father or mother.
If neither parent has the right to administer the property referred to in the preceding paragraph and the third party does not appoint an administrator for that property, the family court may, at the request of a child, any relative of the child or a public prosecutor, appoint an administrator.
Even if a third party has appointed an administrator for the property, the preceding paragraph shall apply if the right of that administrator is extinguished or the replacement of that administrator is required, and the third party does not appoint another administrator.
The provisions of Articles 27 to 29 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the cases referred to in the preceding two paragraphs.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Mandate Provisions
The provisions of Article 654 and Article 655 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where a person who exercises parental authority administers the property of a child and the case referred to in the preceding Article.
Extinctive Prescription of Obligations between Parent and Child That Arise from Administration of Property
Obligations that arise from the administration of property between a person who exercised parental authority and the child shall be extinguished by prescription if not exercised within five years from the time the right of administration of property is extinguished.
If the right of administration of property is extinguished while the child has not yet attained the age of majority and the child has no legal representative, the period in the preceding paragraph shall be calculated from the time the child attains the age of majority or a new legal representative takes office.
Exercise of Parental Authority on Behalf of Child
A person who exercises parental authority with regard to a child shall exercise parental authority in lieu of that child regarding that child's child.

Loss of Parental Authority
Ruling of Loss of Parental Authority
If a father or mother has abused his/her child or abandoned the child in bad faith, or a child's interests are extremely harmed due to considerable difficulty or inappropriateness in the exercise of parental authority by his/her father or mother, the family court may, at the request of the child, any relative of the child, a guardian of a minor, a supervisor of a guardian of a minor, or a public prosecutor, make a ruling of loss of parental authority with regard to the father or mother; provided, however, that this shall not apply if the cause thereof is expected to cease to exist within two years.
Ruling of Suspension of Parental Authority
If a child's interests are harmed due to difficulty or inappropriateness in the exercise of parental authority by his/her father or mother, the family court may, at the request of the child, any relative of the child, a guardian of a minor, a supervisor of a guardian of a minor, or a public prosecutor, make a ruling of suspension of parental authority with regard to the father or mother.
If the family court makes a ruling of suspension of parental authority, it shall determine the period of suspension of parental authority within a period not exceeding two years, taking into account the period expected to be required for the cause thereof to cease to exist, the physical and mental conditions, and the living circumstances of the child, and all other circumstances.
Ruling of Loss of Right of Administration of Property
If a child's interests are harmed due to difficulty or inappropriateness in the exercise of the right of administration of property by his/her father or mother, the family court may, at the request of the child, any relative of the child, a guardian of a minor, a supervisor of a guardian of a minor, or a public prosecutor, make a ruling of loss of the right of administration of property with regard to the father or mother..
Rescission of Ruling of Loss of Parental Authority, Suspension of Parental Authority or Loss of Right of Administration of Property
If the causes in the main clause of Article 834, paragraph (1) of Article 834-2, or the preceding Article have ceased to exist, the family court may, at the request of the person concerned or any relative of his/hers, rescind a ruling of loss of parental authority, suspension of parental authority, or loss of the right of administration of property.
Surrender and Resumption of Parental Authority or Right of Management Administration of Property
If there is an unavoidable reason, a father or mother who exercises parental authority may, with the permission of the family court, surrender parental authority or the right of administration of property.
If the reason in the preceding paragraph has ceased to exist, a father or mother may, with the permission of the family court, resume parental authority or the right of administration of property.


Guardianship
Commencement of Guardianship
Guardianship shall commence in the following cases:

Organs of Guardianship
Guardian
Designation of Guardian of Minor
A person who last exercises parental authority over a minor may designate a guardian of a minor by will; provided that this shall not apply to a person who has no right of administration of property.
If one of the parents who have parental authority has no right of administration of property, the other parent may designate a guardian of a minor pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph.
Appointment of Guardian of Minor
If there is no person to become a guardian of a minor pursuant to the provisions of the preceding Article, the family court may appoint a guardian of a minor at the request of a minor ward or his/her relative, or other interested person. This shall also apply in a case where any vacancy in the position of a guardian of a minor occurs.
Even if there is a guardian of a minor, the family court may appoint a further guardian, when it finds this necessary, at the request of the persons prescribed in the preceding paragraph, or a guardian of a minor, or ex officio.
In the appointment of a guardian of a minor, the family court shall consider the age, the physical and mental condition, and the living and property circumstances of the minor ward, the occupation and personal history of the person to become the guardian, the existence of any vested interest between them (if the person to become the guardian of a minor is a juridical person, its type and content of business and the existence of any vested interest between the minor ward and the juridical person or its representative), the opinion of the minor ward, and all other circumstances.
Application for Appointment of Guardian of Minor by Parents
If a father or mother surrenders parental authority or the right of administration of property, or if the necessity to appoint a guardian of a minor arises as a result of a ruling of loss of parental authority, suspension of parental authority or loss of the right of administration of property, the father or mother shall, without delay, apply to the family court for the appointment of a guardian of a minor.
Appointment of Guardian of Adult
The family court shall appoint ex officio a guardian of an adult if it orders commencement of guardianship.
If the office of a guardian of an adult is vacant, the family court shall appoint a guardian of an adult at the request of an adult ward or his/her relative, or other interested person, or ex officio.
Even if a guardian of an adult has been appointed, the family court may appoint a further guardian, when it finds this necessary, at the request of the persons prescribed in the preceding paragraph, or a guardian of an adult, or ex officio.
In the appointment of a guardian of an adult, the family court shall consider the physical and mental condition and the living and property circumstances of the adult ward, the occupation and personal history of the person to become the guardian, the existence of any vested interest between them (if the person to become a guardian of an adult is a juridical person, its type and content of business and the existence of any vested interest between the adult ward and the juridical person or its representative), the opinion of the adult ward, and all other circumstances.
Surrender of Guardianship
A guardian of an adult may, where any justifiable reason exists, surrender his/her office upon the permission of the family court.
Application for Appointment of New Guardian upon the Surrender of Guardianship
If the necessity to appoint a new guardian arises through a guardian's surrender of office, the guardian shall, without delay, petition the family court to appoint a new guardian.
Replacement of Guardian
If there is an unlawful act, grave misconduct, or other cause not befitting the office of guardianship on the part of a guardian, the family court may replace the guardian at the request of a supervisor of a guardian, a ward or his/her relative, or a public prosecutor, or ex officio.
Causes of Disqualification of Guardian
Any person who falls under any of the following items may not become a guardian:
Supervisor of a Guardian
Designation of Supervisor of Guardian of Minor
A person who may designate a guardian of a minor may designate a supervisor of a guardian of a minor by will.
Appointment of Supervisor of Guardian
The family court may appoint a supervisor of a guardian, when it finds this necessary, at the request of a ward or his/her relative, or a guardian, or ex officio.
Causes of Disqualification of Supervisor of a Guardian
A spouse, lineal relative by blood, or sibling of a guardian may not become a supervisor of a guardian.
Duties of Supervisor of Guardian
The duties of a supervisor of a guardian are as follows:
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Mandate and Guardian Provisions
The provisions of Article 644, Article 654, Article 655, Article 844, Article 846, Article 847, paragraph (2) of Article 861, and Article 862 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a supervisor of a guardian, the provisions of paragraph (3) of Article 840 and Article 857-2 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a supervisor of a guardian of a minor, and the provisions of paragraph (4) of Article 843, Article 859-2 and Article 859-3 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a supervisor of a guardian of an adult.

Affairs of Guardian
Investigation of Property and Preparation of Inventory
A guardian shall, without delay, undertake an investigation of the ward's property, and finalize the investigation and prepare an inventory of property within one month; provided that this period may be extended with the approval of the family court.
An investigation of property and the preparation of an inventory of property shall not be valid unless conducted in the presence of a supervisor of the guardian, if one exists.
Authority Prior to Completion of Inventory of Property
Until a guardian has completed the inventory of property, he/she shall not be entitled to exercise his/her authority unless there is an urgent need; provided that this may not be asserted against a third party in good faith.
Guardian's Duty to Report Claims or Obligations in Relation to Ward
In the case where a guardian has any claim or bears any obligation in relation to a ward, he/she shall report this to the supervisor, if one exists, before undertaking an investigation of property.
If a guardian knows of a claim against a ward and does not report it, this claim is lost.
Application Mutatis Mutandis to the Case Ward Acquires Property under Universal Title
The provisions of the preceding three Articles shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where a ward acquires property under universal title after a guardian has assumed office.
Rights and Duties regarding Personal Supervision of Minor Ward
A guardian of a minor shall have, with respect to the matters prescribed in the Articles 820 to 823 inclusive, the same rights and duties as a person who exercises parental authority; provided that in order to change the plan of education or the residence determined by a person who exercises parental authority, to give permission to carry on business, or to revoke or limit that permission, he/she shall obtain the consent of a supervisor of a guardian of a minor, if one exists.
Exercise of Authority where Multiple Guardians of a Minor Exist
If there are multiple guardians of a minor, they shall exercise their authority jointly.
If there are multiple guardians of a minor, the family court may determine ex officio that some of the guardians should only exercise their authority regarding property.
If there are multiple guardians of a minor, the family court may determine ex officio that each guardian should exercise his/her authority individually or that the multiple guardians should exercise their authority according to a division of labor, with regard to the authority regarding property.
The family court may rescind ex officio a determination made pursuant to the provisions of the preceding two paragraphs.
If there are multiple guardians of a minor, it is sufficient that a manifestation of intention by a third party be made to one guardian.
Respect for Intention and Personal Consideration of Adult Ward
A guardian of an adult, in undertaking affairs related to the life, medical treatment and nursing, and administration of property of an adult ward, shall respect the intention of the adult ward, and consider his/her mental and physical condition and living circumstances.
Administration and Representation over Property
A guardian shall administer the property of a ward and represent a ward in juristic acts concerning his/her property.
The provision of the proviso to Article 824 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Exercise of Authority where Multiple Guardians of Adult
If there are multiple guardians of an adult, the family court may determine ex officio that the guardians should exercise authority jointly or according to a division of labor.
The family court may rescind ex officio a determination made pursuant to the provisions of the preceding paragraph.
If there are multiple guardians of an adult, it is sufficient that a manifestation of intention by a third party be made to one guardian.
Permission regarding Disposition of Real Estate Used for Adult Ward's Residence
A guardian of an adult shall obtain the permission of the family court for sale, rent, cancellation of lease, or establishment of a mortgage, or any other disposition equivalent to these, on the ward's behalf with regard to a building or site used for the adult ward's residence.
Acts in Conflict of Interest
The provisions of Article 826 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a guardian; provided that this shall not apply in the case where there is a supervisor of a guardian.
Expenditure Estimation and Expenses of Affairs of Guardianship
Upon assumption of office, a guardian shall estimate the amount of money that will be required in annual expenditure for the living, education, medical treatment and nursing, and administration of property of the ward.
A guardian shall pay the expenses necessary to undertake the affairs of guardianship out of the property of the ward.
Remuneration to Guardian
The family court may grant reasonable remuneration to a guardian out of the property of the ward, considering the financial capacity of the guardian and the ward and other circumstances.
Supervision of Affairs of Guardianship
A supervisor of a guardian or the family court may, at any time, demand that a guardian submit a report on the affairs of guardianship or an inventory of property, and may investigate the affairs of guardianship or the situation of the property of the ward.
The family court may order any necessary disposition concerning the administration of the property of a ward, or other affairs of guardianship, at the request of a supervisor of a guardian, the ward or his/her relative, or other interested person, or ex officio.
Acts Requiring the Consent of a Supervisor of Guardian
For a guardian, on behalf of a ward, to undertake business or the acts listed in each item of paragraph (1) of Article 13, or to give consent for a minor ward to undertake the same, he/she shall obtain the consent of a supervisor of a guardian, if one exists; provided that this shall not apply to the receipt of principal listed in item (i) of paragraph (1) of Article 13.
A ward or a guardian may rescind acts conducted or consented to by a guardian in violation of the provisions of the preceding Article. In this case, the provisions of Article 20 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the application of the provisions of Articles 121 to 126 inclusive.
Ward's Rescission of Reception of Property etc.
If a guardian has received the property of a ward or the right of a third party against the ward, the ward may rescind that reception. In this case, the provisions of Article 20 shall apply mutatis mutandis.
The provision of the preceding paragraph shall not preclude the application of the provisions of Articles 121 to 126 inclusive.
Exercise of Parental Authority on Behalf of Minor Ward
A guardian of a minor shall exercise parental authority in lieu of a minor ward with respect to that minor ward's child.
The provisions of Articles 853 to 857 inclusive and Articles 861 to 866 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Guardian of Minor with Rights and Duties regarding Property Only
In the case where a person who has parental authority does not have the right of administration of property, a guardian of a minor shall have authority regarding property and that authority only.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Mandate and Parental Authority Provisions
The provisions of Article 644 and Article 830 shall apply mutatis mutandis to guardianship.

Termination of Guardianship
Account of Guardianship
When the office of a guardian comes to an end, he/she or his/her successor shall render an account of his/her administration within two months; provided that this period may be extended with the approval of the family court.
An account of guardianship shall be conducted in the presence of a supervisor of a guardian, if one exists.
Rescission of Contract etc. between a Minor Ward and Guardian of Minor etc.
A person who, as an ex-minor ward, made a contract with a guardian, or the heir of the guardian, after attaining majority but before settlement of the account of guardianship may rescind such contract. The same shall apply to unilateral juristic acts that person makes toward a guardian of a minor or his/her successor.
The provisions of Article 20 and Articles 121 to 126 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Payment of Interest etc. upon Money Refunded
Money to be refunded by a guardian to a ward and money to be refunded by a ward to a guardian shall bear interest from the time the account of guardianship is settled.
If a guardian has expended a ward's money for his/her own benefit, such money shall bear interest from the time of the expenditure. In this case, further damages are incurred by the ward, the guardian shall be liable for such damages.
Application Mutatis Mutandis of Mandate Provisions
The provisions of Article 654 and Article 655 shall apply mutatis mutandis to guardianship.
Extinctive Prescription of Claim That Arises from Guardianship
The provisions of Article 832 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the extinctive prescription of a claim that arises from guardianship between a guardian or a supervisor of a guardian and a ward.
In the case where a juristic act is rescinded pursuant to the provisions of Article 872, the period of the extinctive prescription prescribed in the preceding paragraph commences from the time of that rescission.


Curatorship and Assistance
Curatorship
Commencement of Curatorship
Curatorship shall commence by order of commencement of curatorship.
Appointment etc. of Curator or Temporary Curator
If the family court orders commencement of curatorship, it will appoint a curator ex officio.
The provisions of paragraphs 2 to 4 of Article 843 and from Article 844 to 847 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to a curator.
For acts where there is a conflict of interest between the curator or his/her representative and a person under curatorship, the curator shall apply to the family court for the appointment of a temporary curator; provided that this shall not apply in the case where there is a supervisor of a curator.
Supervisor of Curator
The family court may appoint a supervisor of a curator, if it finds this necessary, at the request of a person under curatorship or his/her relative, or a curator, or ex officio.
The provisions of Article 644, Article 654, Article 655, paragraph (4) of Article 843, Article 844, Article 846, Article 847, Article 850, Article 851, Article 859-2, Article 859-3, paragraph (2) of Article 861, and Article 862 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a supervisor of a curator. In this case, the term 'represent the ward regarding' in item (iv) of Article 851 shall be deemed to be replaced with 'represent a person under curatorship regarding, or give consent for a person under curatorship to undertake the same'.
Order Granting Power of Representation to Curator
At the request of a person prescribed by the main clause of Article 11 or a curator, or a supervisor of a curator, the family court may make an order that grants power of representation to the curator, concerning specified juristic acts for the person under curatorship.
An order referred to in the preceding paragraph made at the request of any person other than the person under curatorship shall require the consent of the person under curatorship.
The family court may rescind an order referred to in paragraph (1), in whole or in part, at the request of a person prescribed by that paragraph.
Affairs of Curatorship and Termination of Office of Curator
A curator, in undertaking the affairs of curatorship, shall respect the intention of the person under curatorship, and consider his/her mental and physical condition and living circumstances.
The provisions of Article 644, Article 859-2, Article 859-3, paragraph (2) of Article 861, Article 862, and Article 863 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the affairs of curatorship, and the provision of the proviso to Article 824 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where a curator represents a person under curatorship based upon an order granting the power of representation referred to in paragraph (1) of the preceding Article.
The provisions of Article 654, Article 655, Article 870, Article 871 and Article 873 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case of termination of office of a curator, and the provisions of Article 832 shall apply mutatis mutandis to claims that arise from curatorship between a curator, or a supervisor of a curator, and a person under curatorship.

Assistance
Commencement of Assistance
Assistance shall commence by order of commencement of assistance.
Appointment etc. of Assistant or Temporary Assistant
If the family court orders commencement of assistance, it will appoint an assistant ex officio.
The provisions of paragraphs (2) to (4) of Article 843 and from Article 844 to 847 inclusive shall apply mutatis mutandis to an assistant.
For acts where there is a conflict of interest between the assistant or his/her representative and a person under assistance, the assistant shall apply to the family court for the appointment of a temporary assistant; provided that this shall not apply in the case where there is a supervisor of an assistant.
Supervisor of Assistant
The family court may appoint a supervisor of an assistant, if it finds this necessary, at the request of a person under assistance, his/her relative, or an assistant, or ex officio.
The provisions of Article 644, Article 654, Article 655, paragraph (4) of Article 843, Article 844, Article 846, Article 847, Article 850, Article 851, Article 859-2, Article 859-3, paragraph (2) of Article 861, and Article 862 shall apply mutatis mutandis to a supervisor of an assistant. In this case, the term 'represent the ward regarding' in item (iv) of Article 851 shall be deemed to be replaced with 'represent a person under assistance regarding, or give consent for a person under assistance to undertake the same.
Order Granting Power of Representation to Assistant
At the request of a person prescribed by the main clause of paragraph (1) of Article 15, an assistant, or a supervisor of an assistant, the family court may make an order that grants power of representation to the assistant, concerning specified juristic acts for the person under assistance.
The provisions of paragraph (2) and paragraph (3) of Article 876-4 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the order referred to in the preceding paragraph.
Affairs of Assistance and Termination of Office of Assistant
The provisions of Article 644, Article 859-2, Article 859-3, paragraph (2) of Article 861, Article 862, Article 863, and paragraph (1) of Article 876-5, shall apply mutatis mutandis to the affairs of assistance, and the provision of the proviso to Article 824 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case where an assistant represents a person under assistance based upon an order granting the power of representation referred to in paragraph (1) of the preceding Article.
The provisions of Article 654, Article 655, Article 870, Article 871 and Article 873 shall apply mutatis mutandis to the case of termination of office of an assistant, and the provisions of Article 832 shall apply mutatis mutandis to claims that arise from assistance between an assistant, or a supervisor of an assistant, and a person under assistance


Support
Supporter under Duty
Lineal relative by blood and siblings have a duty to support each other.
If special circumstances exist, the family court may also impose a duty of support between relatives within the third degree, in addition to the case prescribed in the preceding paragraph.
If an alteration in circumstances arises after an order pursuant to the provision of the preceding paragraph, the family court may revoke that order.
Order of Support
In the case where there exist several persons under a duty to give support, and agreement has not, or cannot be, reached between the parties with respect to the order in which they are to give support, the family court shall determine the order. In the case where there exist several persons entitled to support and the financial capacity of the person under a duty to give support is insufficient to support them all, the same shall apply.
Extent and Form of Support
If agreement has not, or cannot be, reached between the parties with respect to the extent and form of support, the family court shall determine such matters, considering the needs of the person entitled to support, the financial capacity of the person under a duty to give support, and any other related circumstances.
Alteration or Revocation of Agreement or Order with Regard to Support
If an alteration in circumstances arises after an agreement or an order regarding the order of persons under a duty to support, persons entitled to support, or the extent or form of support, the family court may alter or revoke the agreement or the order.
Prohibition of Disposition of Claim for Support
The right to support may not be subject to disposition.
</DOC>
