<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<dataset>
<pair id="H19-1-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="96"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A person who made a manifestation of intention which was induced by duress emanated from a third party may rescind such manifestation of intention on the basis of duress, only if the other party knew or was negligent of such fact.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-1-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="94"/>
<article id="896"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where a fictitious sales contract was formed in collusion with another party, even if the buyer's heir did not know such fact, the seller may assert nullity of the contract in question.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-3-A" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="20"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where A was a minor at the time of the contract, if B demanded a definite answer regarding whether or not A will ratify his/her own acts within the period of one month, and A  failed to give any definite answer within that period, it shall be deemed that A has ratified his/her act.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-3-I" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="20"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where  A was a person under curatorship, and B demanded that A should obtain the ratification of his/her curator C within a period of one month, if A fails to issue a notice to the effect that such ratification has been obtained within that period, it is deemed that A's act has been rescinded.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-3-U" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="114"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where  A entered into a contract with an unauthorized agent of C, if Party B establishes a reasonable period of time for C, demanding a definite answer as to whether or not C ratifies A's acts within that period, and C fails to give any definite answer within that period, C is deemed to have refused to ratify.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-3-E" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="20"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where  A was an adult ward, if B demanded a definite answer about whether or not A's guardian C  ratifies A's act within a period of one month, and C failed to give any definite answer within that period, it is deemed that A's act has been rescinded.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-4-I" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="128"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a sales contract subject to  a condition precedent, the buyer that intentionally damaged the object while it is uncertain whether or not the condition has been fulfilled shall bear liability for damages to the seller whose expectation right is infringed.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-5-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="162"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even if the  possessor started the possession without knowledge and was not negligent of another's ownership of the property in cases where he/she subsequently knew another person's ownership during  possession, the period of prescription shall be calculated as a possessor in bad faith.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-6-A" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="166"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Extinctive prescription for claims with a specified due date commences to run on the time of arrival of such time limit..
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-6-I" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="166"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Extinctive prescription for claims with unspecified due date commences to run on the time of arrival of such obligortime limit.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-6-O" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="300"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even while the holder of a right to retention continues the possession of the retained property, extinctive prescription runs for its secured claim.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-7-2" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="87"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Extended parts of the building shall be regarded as appurtenance..
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-8-A" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="177"/>
</t1>
<t2>
X, who purchased a real estate P from decedent A before the commencement of inheritance, may assert his ownership of P against Y without registration, if Y, who is the obligee of A's sole heir B, seized P in subrogation to B after B's inheritance registration of P.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-10-I" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="302"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Since rights of retention are real rights that include the right to possess properties, holders of rights of retention cannot demand the return of the property retained by way of an action on title based on rights of retention.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-10-O" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="181"/>
<article id="200"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A landowner that leased his/her land and delivered it to a lessee not only may demand the return of such land by way of possessory actions, but also may demand the return of the land by way of actions on title based on landownership, in cases where the land was usurped by a third party.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-11-3" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="177"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where A bought a registered building owned by B, and subsequently that building's ownership preservation registration was made in B's name, if B sold the building to C and registered the transfer,  A may not asset his/her acquisition of ownership of that building.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-11-5" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="177"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In a case where A, B, and C co-own a land, D, who has inherited A's share from A, may assert his/her acquisition of A's share against  B and C without completing the registration.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-12-1" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="350"/>
<article id="372"/>
<article id="304"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A right of retention, a pledge, and a mortgage may also be exercised against Things including monies that the obligor is to receive as a result of the sale, lease or loss of, or damage to, the subject matter of such collateral rights.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-12-3" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="331"/>
<article id="339"/>
</t1>
<t2>
The order of priority of a real estate statutory lien, a real estate pledge, and a mortgage is determined by that of the registration.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-12-4" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="343"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where  a contract that creates a pledge upon a claim that cannot be assigned due to its nature has been made, such contract is void, regardless of whether the pledgee acted in good or bad faith regarding said non-assignability.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-12-5" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="333"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A holder of  a statutory lien on movables may exercise his/her right, even in cases where the movable subject to the statutory lien has been sold and delivered to a third party, if the third party knew of the existence of such statutory lien.movablemovablemovable
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-13-A" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="296"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A holder of a right of retention may retain that thing until his/her claim is satisfied in its entirety..
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-13-I" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="308"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Statutory liens for employer-employee relationships secure salaries paid regularly, but do not secure retirement payments that should be paid when the employee retires.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-13-U" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="346"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In addition to the principal of the secured claim, pledges of real estates shall secure periodic payments including interest only for those that have fallen due in the most recent two years.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-13-E" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="375"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In addition to the principal of the secured claim, mortgages that are not revolving mortgages shall secure periodic payments including interest only for those that have fallen due in the most recent two years.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-13-O" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="398-3"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In addition to the fixed principal, revolving mortgages with a fixed principal shall secure up to the maximum amount with respect to the periodic payments including interest for those that have fallen due in the most recent two years.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-14-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="321"/>
<article id="304"/>
</t1>
<t2>
If the obligor sold the subject matter of a statutory lien to a third party, the holder of the statutory lien for sales of movables may exercise such right against the purchase money claim accrued from the sales .
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-15-I" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="587"/>
</t1>
<t2>
In cases where the registration for the creation of a mortgage has been made for monetary loan claims, but the principal was not delivered in the end, the mortgagor may demand cancellation of such  registration due to the non-existence of  secured claim.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-16-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="395"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A person who uses a mortgaged building based on a lease that may not be asserted against the mortgagee may suspend the vacation of that building to the purchaser for up to 6 months from the time that the purchaser purchased the building in cases where the building was auctioned, if he/she has been using it prior to the commencement of auction proceedings.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-16-2" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="387"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A registered lease may be asserted against  the mortgagee who gave  consent to the lease, if the entire mortgagee who had registered their respective mortgage before the lease's registration gave consent to the lease.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-16-3" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="389"/>
</t1>
<t2>
If a building existed on a mortgaged land at the time it was mortgaged, even if the owner of that building did not have the right to possess the land which may be asserted against the mortgagee, the mortgagee may not auction the building together with the land.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-16-4" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="379"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Holders of superficies created upon mortgaged real estates may not make a claim for the extinction of the mortgage.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-16-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="371"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even if the owner of a mortgaged property acquires fruits derived after the default of the secured claim, it shall not be a case of unjust enrichment.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-17-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="414"/>
</t1>
<t2>
There are cases when compensation of damages may be demanded besides demand for the enforcement of performance.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-17-2" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="414"/>
<article id="415"/>
</t1>
<t2>
There are cases where only compensation of damages may be demanded, while enforcement of performance may not be demanded.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-20-I" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="501"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A third party acquirer of a mortgaged real estate obligormay not subrogate to the secured claim of the obligee against the guarantor.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-26-I" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="653"/>
</t1>
<t2>
The mandate shall terminate when the mandatary is subject to a ruling for the commencement of bankruptcy procedures, but shall not terminate when the mandator is subject to such ruling.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-26-U" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="653"/>
</t1>
<t2>
The mandate shall terminate when the mandatary is subject to an order  for the commencement of guardianship.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-26-O" label="N">
<t1>
<article id="655"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Regardless of the other party's knowledge, the grounds of termination of mandate may not be asserted against the other party unless the other party was notified of the same.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-30-1" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="700"/>
<article id="702"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Even if contrary to the intentions of the principal, management of business may be established, and in that case, the manager may request reimbursement for expenses incurred for the principal  solely to the extent such principal actually enriched.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-30-3" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="698"/>
</t1>
<t2>
Unless a Manager engages in the Management of Business in order to allow a principal to escape imminent danger to the principal's person, reputation or property, the manager must manage the business with due care of a prudent manager.
</t2>
</pair>
<pair id="H19-30-5" label="Y">
<t1>
<article id="701"/>
<article id="645"/>
</t1>
<t2>
A manager must report the progress and results to the principal without delay upon completion of the management of business.
</t2>
</pair>
</dataset>
